
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
   <title>Computers on English Lessons and Computers</title>
   <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/computers/</link>
   <description>Recent content in Computers on English Lessons and Computers</description>
   <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
   <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:30:17 +1000</lastBuildDate>
   
       <atom:link href="https://www.zoom8888.com/computers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
   
     <item>
       <title>Robert the Bruce</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/robert-the-bruce/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/robert-the-bruce/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A reading test: Robert the Bruce and the Spider
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Where was the thread carried safely to?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Post your answer as a comment on the Home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was once a king of Scotland whose name was Robert Bruce. He had need to be both brave and wise, for the times in which he lived were wild and rude. The King of England was at war with him, and had led a great army into Scotland to drive him out of the land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle after battle had been fought. Six times had Bruce led his brave little army against his foes; and six times had his men been beaten, and driven into flight. At last his army was scattered, and he was forced to hide himself in the woods and in lonely places among the mountains. One rainy day, Bruce lay on the ground under a rude shed, listening to the patter of the drops on the roof above him. He was tired and sick at heart, and ready to give up all hope. It seemed to him that there was no use for him to try to do anything more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he lay thinking, he saw a spider over his head, making ready to weave her web. He watched her as she toiled slowly and with great care. Six times she tried to throw her frail thread from one beam to another, and six times it fell short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Poor thing!&amp;rdquo; said Bruce: &amp;ldquo;you, too, know what it is to fail.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the spider did not lose hope with the sixth failure. With still more care, she made ready to try for the seventh time. Bruce almost forgot his own troubles as he watched her swing herself out upon the slender line. Would she fail again? No! The thread was carried safely to the beam, and fastened there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I, too, will try a seventh time!&amp;rdquo; cried Bruce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He arose and called his men together. He told them of his plans, and sent them out with messages of cheer to his disheartened people. Soon there was an army of brave Scotsmen around him. Another battle was fought, and the King of England was glad to go back into his own country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>A Tale of Two Jackets.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/a-tale-of-two-jackets/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/a-tale-of-two-jackets/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew walks out of his meeting, completely exhausted. After three long days of negotiating, he has finally worked out a deal that is sure to get him a promotion. Despite the fact that he has an early flight back to Sydney in the morning, Andrew decides to have a few drinks at the pub across the street. He has been in London for three days and has not seen any of the city. He cannot leave without at least visiting a pub, he thinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He quickly crosses the street and walks through the blue door of the pub. He notices a coat rack next to the door and carefully hangs his jacket from one of the hooks. Andrew does not really consider it to be his jacket though. It was his father&amp;rsquo;s jacket, but it was passed down to Andrew after his father died last year. Almost every memory Andrew has of his dad involves him wearing the bright red coat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew walks to the bar and orders a drink. After he has finished, the bartender asks if he wants another drink. Andrew checks his watch and sees his plane is leaving in five hours and decides he needs to go. He regrets picking a flight so early in the morning, but knows he will be able to sleep on the plane. He pays for his drink, grabs his jacket, and leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has gotten much colder outside since Andrew went into the pub, so he slips his jacket on. At least, he tries to slip it on. He sticks his arm in the sleeve, but the hole at the end is too small for his hand. He tries the other sleeve, but the jacket is too small to stretch across his back. He takes it off and looks at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like a shrunken version of his jacket. He checks the pocket and finds a wallet that is definitely not his. He opens it up and sees an ID with a picture of a woman. Her name is Erin. She has dark brown hair and green eyes. A cute girl, Andrew thinks, but he does not have time to worry about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He returns to the bar and checks the coat rack. His coat is gone. There are three black coats and a brown one, but not a single red. He walks around the bar thinking that maybe Erin got cold and put his jacket on, but there are no women in the whole place. He stands still, trying to decide what to do. He cannot leave his dad&amp;rsquo;s jacket in London and Erin
He types the address from her ID into his phone and sees that her house is only a few blocks away. He can stop by her place, trade jackets, and still make it back to his hotel with a little bit of time to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He walks through the night. It is getting colder and his thin dress shirt does not keep him warm. He finds the house and knocks on the door. When the door finally opens, the woman standing behind it is definitely not Erin. This woman is in her eighties with bright white hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Does a woman named Erin live here?&amp;rdquo; Andrew asks her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No. No one lives here but me,&amp;rdquo; she answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew digs through the pocket of the jacket and hands the old woman Erin&amp;rsquo;s ID. &amp;ldquo;Do you know her?&amp;rdquo; he asks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh yes, that&amp;rsquo;s the girl who lived here before me. I saw her when she was moving out. She&amp;rsquo;s a cute little thing, isn&amp;rsquo;t she?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you know how I can contact her? It&amp;rsquo;s kind of urgent.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well I don&amp;rsquo;t really know her. I could call the landlord. See if he knows anything.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well if it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too much trouble,&amp;rdquo; Andrew says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No trouble at all.&amp;rdquo; The woman invites him in and he sits on the couch. She goes into the kitchen and he hears her talking on the phone. He looks through the wallet, trying to find any clues about her, but all he finds are a couple of credit cards and a picture of her and some friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She must be pretty special,&amp;rdquo; the old woman says as she walks into the living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew&amp;rsquo;s head jerks up as he realizes he is staring at the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, no. I&amp;rsquo;ve never met her,&amp;rdquo; Andrew says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The woman looks suspicious but hands him a piece of paper. &amp;ldquo;The landlord says he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to contact her but he did give me the name of a club she likes to go to. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;ll help.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew types the address written on the paper into his phone and sees it is a ten minute walk away. And he sees that his plane leaves in four hours. He thanks the old woman and
Inside the club, he searches through the crowd but cannot find Erin anywhere. Nobody looks anything like her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He steps outside the club and leans against the wall. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t even notice the woman leaning against the wall next to him wearing a red jacket that is clearly too big for her. She notices him though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That jacket would be warmer if you were wearing it,&amp;rdquo; she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew looks up to see Erin staring right at him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait, you&amp;rsquo;re Erin,&amp;rdquo; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know,&amp;rdquo; she says. &amp;ldquo;But that&amp;rsquo;s weird that you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for you all night. You&amp;rsquo;re wearing my jacket. We accidentally swapped jackets at the pub earlier.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How did you find me?&amp;rdquo; She smiles as she says this. Her smile is a lot more beautiful in person, Andrew thinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a long story.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait, I was at the pub two hours ago. Have you really been chasing me around for that long?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well I was chasing the jacket, really,&amp;rdquo; Andrew says, starting to blush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I like a person that&amp;rsquo;s committed to his jacket,&amp;rdquo; Erin says as she slides off Andrew&amp;rsquo;s jacket and hands it to him. He slips it over his shoulders and feels Erin&amp;rsquo;s lingering warmth. &amp;ldquo;I like long stories. Want to get a cup of coffee and tell me about your night?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sure.&amp;rdquo; Andrew smiles at her and knows he will miss his plane in a few hours, but he does not care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glossary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bartender: a person who mixes and serves drinks at a pub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dig through: to search inside something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dress shirt: a formal white shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ID (Identification Card): a card with your photo, name and other information about you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jerk up: to move with a sudden short movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;landlord: an owner of an apartment or house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lingering: remaining and still not disappearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rack: an object with hooks for hanging things on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;slide off: to remove something easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;slip on: to put clothes on quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;trade: to give something to someone and receive something in return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Articles-Brexit</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/articles-brexit/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/articles-brexit/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The two articles in English are a/an and the.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word a (which becomes an when the next word begins with a vowel - a, e, i, o, u) is called the indefinite article because the noun it goes with is indefinite or general.
The word the is known as the definite article and indicates a specific thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking on _ visit to _ hospital, Boris Johnson refused to rule out _ UK leaving _ EU on 31 October, contradicting statements made by _ chancellor this morning. He said that Corbyn should “man up” and back _ election. No 10 suggested yesterday that _ government could go “on strike” and refuse to do anything until _ election took place but _ threat appeared to soften today. After previously insisting they would “do _ bare minimum to keep _country running”, Johnson said this afternoon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, an, the, the, the, a, a, the, the, the, an&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a, a, the, the, the, an, the, an, the, the, the&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, a, a, the, a, a, the, the, the, an, the&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, an, the, the, the, an, the, the, a, a, the&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post your answer as a comment on the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Too, to, two - Brexit</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/to-to-too-brexit/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/to-to-too-brexit/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A lesson for today, &amp;ldquo;Too, to and two&amp;rdquo;.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boris Johnson is offering parliament more time _ pass his Brexit deal in return for an election on December 12. The prime minister will tonight start his third attempt _ send voters _ the polls by tabling a motion under the Fixed-term Parliaments Act. MPs will vote on Monday on whether the UK will have its first December election since 1923. _ thirds of MPs need _ vote for the poll. Is it _ late to hold an election before Brexit?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two, too, to, to, to, to&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to, to, to, Two, too, to&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to, to, to, Two, to, too&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;too, to, two, to, to, to&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post your answer as a comment on the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The correct answer for our recent test &amp;ldquo;Too, to and two. Fill in the gaps: Brexit&amp;rdquo; is 3. Good work everyone. To read previous lessons scroll further down to &amp;ldquo;Recent Lessons&amp;rdquo;, on the Home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The semicolon.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/run-on-sentences/</link>
       <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/run-on-sentences/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;You can separate two clauses without using a conjunction by using a semicolon. The semicolon or semi-colon ; is a punctuation mark that separates major sentence elements. A semicolon can be used between two closely related independent clauses, provided they are not already joined by a coordinating conjunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rihanna releases a lip gloss; people buy it.
Michael Jordan puts out some new trainers; people buy them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An independent clause contains one subject/predicate pair and expresses a complete thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music makes my life worth living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple sentence is made up of only one independent clause:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music makes my life worth living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A run-on sentence is made up of two or more independent clauses that are not joined correctly or which should be made into separate sentences. A run-on sentence is defined by its grammatical structure, not its length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect: My favourite band is in town they are performing now.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Correct: My favourite band is in town. They are performing now.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Correct: My favourite band is in town, and they are performing now.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comma splice is the incorrect use of a comma to join two independent clauses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect: I love classical music, it makes me feel joyful.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Correct: I love classical music because it makes me feel joyful.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Correct: I love classical music; it makes me feel joyful.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A compound sentence contains two or more independent clauses that are correctly joined by a comma plus a coordinating conjunction or by a semicolon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music means a lot to me, and certain songs bring wonderful memories to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comma plus a coordinating conjunction can connect independent clauses correctly. There are seven coordinating conjunctions (sometimes remembered by the acronym &amp;ldquo;fanboys&amp;rdquo;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complex sentence contains one independent clause and one or more dependent clauses. The dependent clause begins with a subordinating conjunction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always think of summer whenever they play that song.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Your or you&#39;re</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/your-or-youre/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 15:20:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/your-or-youre/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Your
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Your is the second person possessive adjective, used to describe something as belonging to you. Your is always followed by a noun or gerund.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
What is your name?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Is this your pen?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Your book is on the table.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
This is your chair and this is mine.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
You’re&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re is the contraction of &amp;ldquo;you are&amp;rdquo; and is often followed by the present participle (verb form ending in -ing).&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re going to be late.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Is that what you’re wearing?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I think you’re lying.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
If you’re ready, we can go.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps:
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
_ the cream in my coffee.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
_ the salt in my stew.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
The shadow of _ smile when you have gone will colour all my dreams and light the dawn.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. You&amp;rsquo;re, your, you&amp;rsquo;re.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
b. Your, you&amp;rsquo;re, you&amp;rsquo;re.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
c. You&amp;rsquo;re, you&amp;rsquo;re, your.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Post your work as a comment on the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>A reading test - Deepika</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/reading-test-deepika/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/reading-test-deepika/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since Deepika Padukone and Ranveer Singh made their relationship official by getting hitched, people have time and again questioned them about their plans on starting a family together. Deepika recently opened up about all the rumours surrounding her pregnancy. Speaking about the same, Deepika reportedly said that she is not surprised by her pregnancy rumours as according to her it is the said expectation in the society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Deepika not surprised about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting hitched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People have time and again questioned them about their plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Her pregnancy rumours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post your answer as a comment on the Home page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Determiners</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/determiners/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/determiners/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Determiners are words placed in front of a noun to make it clear what the noun refers to. There are about 50 determiners in English. Here are some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definite article : the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indefinite articles : a, an&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstratives: this, that, these, those&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pronouns and possessive determiners : my, your, his, her, its, our, their&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantifiers : a few, a little, much, many, a lot of, most, some, any, enough&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numbers : one, ten, thirty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributives : all, both, half, either, neither, each, every&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Difference words : other, another&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-determiners : such, what, rather, quite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose the correct determiners for this example paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I fall in love, it will be forever, or I&amp;rsquo;ll never fall in love. In _ restless world like _ is, love is ended before it&amp;rsquo;s begun and too _ moonlight kisses seem to cool in _ warmth of _ sun. When I give _ heart, it will be completely, or I&amp;rsquo;ll never give _ heart, and _ moment I can feel _  you feel _ way too is when I fall in love with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a, this, many, my, the, my, the, the, that, that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this, that, a, many, the, the, my, the, my, that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a, this, the, that, the, that, my, the, my, many&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;many, this, that, that, the, the, a, the, my, my&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a, this, many, the, the, my, my, the, that, that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;many, this, a, my, the, my, the, that, the, that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post your answer as a comment on the Home page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Prepositions of time and place - in, on, at.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/prepositions-of-time-and-place/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/prepositions-of-time-and-place/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;There are over one hundred prepositions in English, here is a list of common prepositions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;above, about, across, against, along, among, around, at, before, behind, below, beneath, beside, between, beyond, by, down, during, except, for, from, in, inside, into, like, near, of, off, on, since, to, toward, through, under, until, up, upon, with and within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even advanced learners of English find prepositions difficult, there are hardly any rules as to when to use which preposition. The only way to learn prepositions is by looking them up in a dictionary, reading a lot in English and learning useful phrases off by heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepositions of time and place, in, on, at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In usually indicates the largest time or place.&lt;br&gt;
On is the second largest.&lt;br&gt;
At is the smallest time or place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Today is a windy day here _ Sydney. I am _ the bus traveling to my office, it is so windy today, I should have stayed _ home.&lt;br&gt;
My office is _ Sydney, Australia. It is _ George Street _ 79 George Street, next to the train station.
My office has a party this year, _ December _ Monday, the 4th, it starts _ 5.00PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in, on at, at, in, on, in, on, at&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on, in, at, at, in, on, at, in, on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at, in, on, at, on, in, on, in, at&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in, on, at, in, on, at, in, on, at&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on, in, at, at, in, on, in, at, on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in, at, on, on, at, in, at, in, on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Too, to and two - Mumbai.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/too-to-and-two-mumbai/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/too-to-and-two-mumbai/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never been - Mumbai, it is one of - cities I would like - visit in India, the other being New Delhi. Someone told me not - visit Mumbai in the summer as it is - hot, and that winter is regarded as the appropriate time - visit Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. to, two, to, too, to, to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. to, to, two, too, to, to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. to, two, to, to, too, to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. to, to, to, to, two, too&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post your answer as a comment on the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is often confusion over the words too and to. Both words have two uses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too has two uses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too means as well or also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can do it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you think that too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too portrays the idea of in excess or more than it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cat is too chubby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shoes were too expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad to hear you smoke. A man should always have an occupation of some kind. There are far too many idle men in London as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To has two uses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To is used in expressions like to walk, to run, to paint, etc. (These are all verbs in their infinitive forms.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to run around the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you tell her what to think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To is used in expressions like to the park, to the postman, agree to a proposal. (The word to in these examples is a preposition.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She handed the parcel to the stranger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to the park&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Trust in a relationship.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/trust/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/trust/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A writing test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had feedback on your writing from a native speaker? What did I do right? What did I do wrong? How can I fix it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write at least two sentences and I will correct your grammar, punctuation and spelling. I will also give you a score of 1 - 10, where 10 is excellent. This score is how I perceive your overall writing skills, it is not related to the IELTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a few sentences about “What is trust in a relationship”. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is a choice to be available, vulnerable and transparent in a relationship. Trust is much more than a gut feeling or a blind faith in someone. It’s merit-based. For this reason, trust is completely different than love and forgiveness. Love and forgiveness can’t be earned (only given freely), but trust can’t be given freely; it must be earned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No SMS texting such as u, r, ur, lol etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No slang words such as wanna, gonna, shoulda, bro, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check your spelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalise the first person pronoun ‘I’ even if it is in the body of a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin a sentence with a capital letter and end it with a full stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insert a single space after but not before a full stop or a comma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write at least two sentences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be offended if your mark is lower than you expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proofread your work a few times before posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be shy, give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post your work as a comment on the Home page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The articles - Pune</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/articles-pune/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 01:00:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/articles-pune/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pune is _ sprawling city in _ western Indian state of Maharashtra. It was once _ base of _ Peshwas (prime ministers) of _ Maratha Empire, which lasted from 1674 to 1818. It&amp;rsquo;s known for _ elegant building, _ grand Aga Khan Palace, built in 1892 and now _ memorial to Mahatma Gandhi, whose ashes are preserved in _ garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a, a, an, the, the, the, the, the, the,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, an, a, the, the, the, a, the, the&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a, the, the, the, the, an, the, a, the,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, the, the, the, an, a, the, the, a,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an, the, a, the, a, the, the, the, the,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two articles in English are a/an and the. The word a (which becomes an when the next word begins with a vowel (a, e, i, o, u) is called the indefinite article because the noun it goes with is indefinite or general. The word the is known as the definite article and indicates a specific thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The articles.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-articles/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 15:20:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-articles/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
English is quite often _ language of choice when speaking to _ international audience at _ conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a, an, the&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an, a, the&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, a, an&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, an, a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an, the, a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two articles in English are a/an and the. The word a (which becomes an when the next word begins with a vowel (a, e, i, o, u) is called the indefinite article because the noun it goes with is indefinite or general. The word the is known as the definite article and indicates a specific thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Riding or driving?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/riding-or-driving/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 15:20:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/riding-or-driving/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Anything with four or more wheels, like a car, a bus, a truck or a train, we drive. Anything with two wheels or that we straddle, like a horse, a bike, motorbike or scooter, we ride, even though you need a driving licence to ride a motorbike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can ride a bicycle.
I can ride a horse.
I can ride a motorcycle.
I am riding a motorcycle.
I am riding on a motorcycle with George.
I can drive a car.
I am driving to work.
I am in my car driving to work.
I am riding in the train to work.
I am riding on the bus to work.
I am riding on the bus to work, the driver is a woman.
I am riding in a car to work, George is driving.
I had never driven such a powerful car before.
I hadn’t ridden a bike for over twenty years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are driving a motorcycle you are riding it. If you are on the back while someone else is driving it, you are riding on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we are passengers rather than drivers, we ride in cars and trains, but we tend to ride on buses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than _ by bus I decided to _ my motorbike as it was such a nice day. My girlfriend however is afraid of _ pillion so she caught the bus at the stop outside my house. Along the way I passed the bus and waved to her, she was _ in the back of the bus and I noticed that the bus was _ by a woman wearing a smart uniform and a cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. ride, riding, riding, driven, travel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. driven, ride, riding, travel, riding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. ride, driven, riding, riding, travel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. travel, ride, riding, riding, driven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. travel, riding, driven, riding, riding&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Third Person</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-third-person/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 15:20:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-third-person/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The term third person refers to someone else, i.e., not the writer or a group including the writer (I, me, we, us) or the writer&amp;rsquo;s audience (you). Whenever you use a noun (as opposed to pronoun), it is in the third person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personal pronouns (I, you, he, she, it, we, you, they) are grouped into one of three categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First person: I and we
Second person: you
Third person: He, She, it and they&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With third person singular, the pronouns reflect gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Masculine gender: He, him, his
Feminine gender: She, her, hers
Neuter gender: It, its&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many languages, the verb takes a form dependent on this person and whether it is singular or plural. In English, this happens with the verb to be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am (first-person singular)
you are, thou art (second-person singular)
he, she, one or it is (third-person singular)
we are (first-person plural)
you are, (second-person plural)
they are (third-person plural)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third person pronouns are an essential tool in writing because they are less cumbersome and cut down on the repetition of nouns. Third person pronouns are widely used in writing, for anything from fictional and traditional forms of academic writing to product descriptions, guides, blogs, articles and more. Singular third person pronouns are he, she, it, his, hers, him and her, and third person plural pronouns are they, them and their.” The number of people to which you are referring should always match the pronoun you choose (“he” to refer to one male, “they” to refer to more than one male).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing in third person is writing from the third person point of view and uses pronouns like he, she, it, or they. It differs from the first person, which uses pronouns such as I and me, and from the second person, which uses pronouns such as you and yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a few sentences in the third person. For example:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When she said hello her eyes clicked onto his face, the breath whooshed out of his body and everything froze for a second, as though through a camera lens, zoomed in all the way, the world pausing for that tiny span of time between the opening and closing of the shutter.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post your work as a comment on the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Sorry, excuse me or pardon me.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/sorry/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 15:20:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/sorry/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;In actual use there is a great deal of overlap and all of these expressions can be heard at some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &amp;ldquo;sorry&amp;rdquo; when you regret doing something, and would try not to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry. I think I spilt your drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You use &amp;ldquo;excuse me&amp;rdquo; in advance of doing something that might disturb someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excuse me. Could I borrow your pen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pardon me is used to apologise for minor acts of rudeness, or to ask for repetition of something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{burp} Oh, pardon me!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Pardon me, I didn&amp;rsquo;t hear you clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying those rules, you should use &amp;ldquo;Excuse me. Does this train go to the city?&amp;rdquo; As you are using it in advance of asking a question that might disturb the person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a sentence using sorry, excuse me, or pardon me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Writing a sentence.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/writing-a-sentence/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 15:20:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/writing-a-sentence/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Your sentence should begin with a capital letter.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-name-is&#34;&gt;My name is&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The names of people, places and countries (proper nouns) should also begin with a capital letter. Always capitalise the first person pronoun &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-name-is-andrew-and-i-live-in-australia&#34;&gt;My name is Andrew and I live in Australia.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End your sentence with a full stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it yourself, write a sentence today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Around or round?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/around-or-round/</link>
       <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 15:20:15 +0900</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/around-or-round/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Around is usually an adverb meaning in a circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Round is usually a noun meaning a circular object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use around and round when we refer to movements in circles or from one place to another. Around and round can both be used. Around is more common in American English. Round is a little more common in spoken English:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The office chairs are placed around a round table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earth goes round the sun. (movement in circles)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent a very pleasant day walking around the town. (movement from one place to another)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now they are retired, they are planning a trip around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also commonly use around and round in phrasal verbs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you pass these application forms around to all the people present?
We spent the whole day moving round some furniture in the bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around and round also mean ‘in different places’ and ‘here and there’:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People were panicking and running round and shouting.
Where&amp;rsquo;s Jill? I know she&amp;rsquo;s around somewhere in the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around can also mean approximately: How old do you think the castle is? I&amp;rsquo;d say around 500 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some contexts, British speakers use round and around interchangeably; for
example, either &amp;lsquo;He put his arm round her,&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;He put his arm around her.&amp;rsquo; Americans use around in contexts in which most British speakers prefer round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word round has five grammatical functions: noun, verb, adjective, adverb, and preposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fighter was able to go another round. (noun)&lt;br&gt;
We watched as the runner rounded first base. (verb)&lt;br&gt;
Do you want a round plate or a square one? (adjective)&lt;br&gt;
The bridge was out, so we had to go round. (adverb)&lt;br&gt;
The tiger ran round the tree. (preposition)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around was formed from the noun round by adding the prefix a-, a variation of the prefix on-, creating an adverb that meant &amp;lsquo;in a circle.&amp;rsquo; There&amp;rsquo;s a general preference among British speakers to use round for “definite, specific movement,&amp;rsquo; and around in contexts that are less definite. For example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She turned round.&lt;br&gt;
A bus came round the corner.&lt;br&gt;
She wandered around for ages.&lt;br&gt;
The computer cost around £3,000.&lt;br&gt;
According to a rumour circulating around the track, he&amp;rsquo;s using steroids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>A cover letter</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/cover-letter/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/cover-letter/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A cover letter is your first introduction to a potential employer, so it needs to show that you are a suitable candidate. A cover letter is an important document that introduces your resume to potential employers and highlights your suitability for the role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a cover letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Smith&lt;br&gt;
23 Third Street&lt;br&gt;
Sydney&lt;br&gt;
Australia 2001&lt;br&gt;
61 2 233987&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:john.smith@gmail.com&#34;&gt;john.smith@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25th January, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Human Resources Department&lt;br&gt;
The IBM Corporation&lt;br&gt;
BSL Office Complex&lt;br&gt;
1 Minto Rd&lt;br&gt;
Dhaka&lt;br&gt;
Bangladesh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir/Madam,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached is my completed application for employment as an IT Engineer, your ref:4567, together with three references, my employment history and copies of my academic certificates, as requested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Your signature goes here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Smith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encl: 6&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>A little white lie.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/little-white-lie/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/little-white-lie/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever told a little white lie?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little white lie is a harmless or trivial lie, especially one told to avoid hurting someone&amp;rsquo;s feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She told me I was the only man she had ever truly loved, but I know this was a little white lie as I have seen her with many other men before.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>A reading test - gossip.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/reading-test-gossip/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/reading-test-gossip/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Do women gossip more than men?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gossip is often maligned. But it’s an important part of social cooperation and information sharing – and is complimentary more often than you might think. But despite the longstanding perception that women gossip more than men, there’s no evidence that this is the case. Gossip is often treated with disdain or hostility. But it can be useful for small groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an important distinction to make here about how most of us define gossip – as a way of trash-talking someone not present – and how scientists do. In social science, gossip usually is defined as communication about a person who isn’t present in a way that involves evaluation of that person, good or bad. This kind of informal communication is crucial for sharing information. Gossip is necessary for social cooperation; it’s largely this kind of talk that cements social bonds and clarifies social norms.
Do you believe that women gossip more than men?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. About the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post your answer as a comment on the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>A writing test</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/english/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/english/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had feedback on your writing from a native speaker?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I do right?
What did I do wrong?
How can I fix it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out what your English level is on a scale of 1 - 9  (A1/2 - C2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a few sentences about &amp;ldquo;What is trust in a relationship&amp;rdquo;. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is a choice to be available, vulnerable and transparent in a relationship.  Trust is much more than a gut feeling or a blind faith in someone. It’s merit-based. For this reason, trust is completely different than love and forgiveness. Love and forgiveness can’t be earned (only given freely), but trust can’t be given freely; it must be earned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few tips..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid SMS texting and slang words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write at least two sentences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be offended if your mark is lower than you expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be shy, give it a try.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proofread your work a few times before posting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Accents and Dialects</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/accents-and-dialects/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/accents-and-dialects/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Accents&lt;br&gt;
Local accents are part of local dialects. Any dialect of English has unique features in pronunciation, vocabulary, and grammar. The term “accent” describes only the first of these, namely, pronunciation. Non-native speakers of English tend to carry over the intonation and phonemic inventory from their mother tongue into their English speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among native English speakers, many different accents exist. Some regional accents, such as Pennsylvania Dutch English, are easily identified by certain characteristics. Further variations are to be found within regions, for example, towns located less than 10 miles (16 km) from the City of Manchester such as Bolton, Oldham and Salford, each have distinct accents, all of which form the Lancashire accent, yet in extreme cases are different enough to be noticed even by a non-local listener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also much room for misunderstanding between people from different regions, as the way one word is pronounced in one accent (for example, petal in American English) will sound like a different word in another accent (for example, pearl in Scottish English).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dialects&lt;br&gt;
Dialects can be usefully defined as sub-forms of languages which are, in general, mutually comprehensible;. British linguists distinguish dialect from accent, which refers only to pronunciation. Thus, any educated English speaker can use the vocabulary and grammar of Standard English, but different speakers use their own local words for everyday objects or actions, regional accent, or Received Pronunciation, which within the U.K. is considered an accent distinguished by class rather than by region. American linguists, however, include pronunciation differences as part of the definition of regional or social dialects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combination of differences in pronunciation and use of local words may make some English dialects almost unintelligible to speakers from other regions. The major native dialects of English are often divided by linguists into the three general categories of the British Isles dialects, those of North America, those of Australasia, and those of South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dialect of British English which is presented in dictionaries is usually known as Received Pronunciation (English as spoken by the upper class and the Queen, for example), or simply RP. Like other accents, RP is subject to variation and change:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Accounting Terms</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/accounting-terms/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/accounting-terms/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Business people studying English as a second language have specific language needs, and it’s crucial that these language students can express themselves clearly and unambiguously in their working lives. A basic knowledge of accounting terms is important for successful business negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accounting; process of identifying, measuring, and reporting financial information of an entity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accounting Equation; assets = liabilities + equity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accounts Payable; money owed to creditors, vendors, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accounts Receivable; money owed to a business, i.e. credit sales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accrual Accounting; a method in which income is recorded when it is earned and expenses are recorded when they are incurred, all independent of cash flow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accruals; a list of expenses that have been incurred and expensed, but not paid or a list of sales that have been completed, but not yet billed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amortization; gradual reduction of amounts in an account over time, either assets or liabilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asset; property with a cash value that is owned by a business or individual&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audit Trail; a record of every transaction, when it was done, by whom and where, used by auditors when validating the financial statement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auditors; third party accountants who review an entity’s financial statements for accuracy and provide a statement to that effect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balance Sheet; summary of a company’s financial status, including assets, liabilities, and equity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bookkeeping; recording financial information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Budgeting; the process of assigning forecasted income and expenses to accounts, which amounts will be compared to actual income and expense for analysis of variances&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital Stock; found in the equity portion of the balance sheet describing the number of shares sold to shareholders at a predetermined value per share, also called “common stock” or “preferred stock”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital Surplus; found in the equity portion of the balance sheet accounting for the amount shareholders paid that is greater or lesser than the “capital stock” amount&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalized Expense; expenses that are accumulated, not expensed as incurred, to be amortized over a period of time; i.e. the development cost of a new product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chart of Accounts; a listing of a company’s accounts and their corresponding numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash-Basis Accounting; a method in which income and expenses are recorded when they are paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash Flow; a summary of cash received and disbursed showing the beginning and ending amounts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing the Books/Year End Closing; the process of reversing the income and expense for a fiscal or calendar year and netting the amount into “retained earnings”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost Accounting; a type of accounting that focuses on recording, defining, and reporting costs associated with specific operating functions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit; an account entry with a negative value for assets, and positive value for liabilities and equity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debit; an account entry with a positive value for assets, and negative value for liabilities and equity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Departmental Accounting; separating operating divisions into their own sub entities on the income statement, showing individual income, expenses, and net profit by entity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depreciation; recognizing the decrease in the value of an asset due to age and use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dividends; amounts paid to shareholders out of current or retained earnings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Double-Entry Bookkeeping; system of accounting in which every transaction has a corresponding positive and negative entry (debits and credits)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equity; money owed to the owner or owners of a company, also known as “owner’s equity”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial Accounting; accounting focused on reporting an entity’s activities to an external party; ie: shareholders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial Statement; a record containing the balance sheet and the income statement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed Asset; long-term tangible property; building, land, computers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Ledger; a record of all financial transactions within an entity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodwill; an intangible asset reflecting the value of an entity in excess of its tangible assets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Income Statement; a summary of income and expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inventory; merchandise purchased for resale at a profit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inventory Valuation; the method to set the book value of unsold inventory: i.e. “LIFO,” last in, first out; “FIFO,” first in, first out; “average,” an average cost over a given period, “last cost,” the cost based on the last purchase; “standard,” a “deemed” amount related to but not tied to a specific purchase, “serialized,” based on a uniquely identifiable serial number or character of each inventory item&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invoice; the original billing from the seller to the buyer, outlining what was purchased and the terms of sale, payment, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job Costing; system of tracking costs associated with a job or project (labor, equipment, etc) and comparing with forecasted costs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal; a record where transactions are recorded, also known as an “account”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liability; money owed to creditors, vendors, etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquid Asset; cash or other property that can be easily converted to cash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loan; money borrowed from a lender and usually repaid with interest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Master Account; an account on the general ledger that subtotals the “subsidiary accounts” assigned to it; i.e. Cash might be the master account for a list of depository accounts at banks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Net Income; money remaining after all expenses and taxes have been paid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non Cash Expense; recognizing the decrease in the value of an asset; i.e. depreciation and amortization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-operating Income; income generated from non-recurring transactions; ie: sale of an old building&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note; a written agreement to repay borrowed money; sometimes used in place of “loan”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operating Income; income generated from regular business operations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Income; income generated from other than regular business operations, i.e. interest, rents, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Payroll; a list of employees and their wages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posting; the process of entering then permanently saving or “archiving” accounting data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profit; see net income;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profit/Loss Statement; see ;income statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reconciliation; the process of matching one set of data to another; i.e. the bank statement to the check register, the accounts payable journal to the general ledger, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retained Earnings; the amount of net profit retained and not paid out to shareholders over the life of the business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revenue; total income before expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shareholder Equity; the capital and retained earnings in an entity attributed to the shareholders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-Entry Bookkeeping; system of accounting in which transactions are entered into one account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statement of Account; a summary of amounts owed to a vendor, lender, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsidiary Accounts; the subaccounts that are totaled on the financial statement under “master accounts;” i.e. “Cash-ABC Bank” might be one of several subsidiary accounts that are subtotaled under “Cash”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplies; assets purchased to be consumed by the entity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasury Stock; shares purchased by the entity from shareholders, reducing shareholder equity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write-down/Write-off; an accounting entry that reduces the value of an asset due to an impairment of that asset; i.e. the account receivable from the bankrupt customer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>An exclamation mark!</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/exclamation-mark-2/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/exclamation-mark-2/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;An exclamation mark or point is a type of punctuation mark that goes at the end of a sentence and essentially looks like a full stop with a vertical line over it:&lt;br&gt;
!&lt;br&gt;
Exclamation marks are used to express excitement, surprise, astonishment, or any other such strong emotion.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I am excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No! he yelled. Do it now!
What on earth are you doing! Stop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When used in a quote, exclamation marks should be inside the quotation marks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary said, &amp;ldquo;I like chocolate a lot!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not add a full stop after a sentence that ends with the an exclamation mark. The exclamation mark will be suffice to end the sentence. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Do not add a space before an exclamation mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve asked you not to sing la Marseillaise!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid using multiple exclamation marks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exclamation mark has a clear role inside the English language. Increasing the number of exclamation or question marks at the end of a sentence might appear to increase the overall emphasis, but in reality it just makes your text ugly and informal. One is enough to convey your feelings in conventional English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correct&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s 8.30am and time I had a coffee break!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s 8.30am and time I had a coffee break!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Aught and ought</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/aught-or-ought/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/aught-or-ought/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Aught is actually a synonym for naught, which means zero or nothing. It can also mean &amp;lsquo;to own or possess&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;to owe someone or something&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;to be obligated to someone&amp;rsquo;, when used as a verb. When used as an adjective, it means &amp;lsquo;possessed of&amp;rsquo;. In its archaic form, it meant &amp;lsquo;possession, as of property or an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although aught and ought are sometimes interchanged, there are subtle differences in meaning, and &amp;lsquo;ought’&amp;rsquo; is more commonly used now, though usually in the spoken rather than in the written form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a noun, ought means &amp;lsquo;duty&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;obligation&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, ought is most commonly used as an auxiliary verb, and it can be used to express a number of things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duty or obligation: Everybody ought to donate to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justice or morality: The thief ought to be ashamed. The thief ought to be punished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appropriate behaviour: You ought to visit the sick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probability: That ought to be your taxi now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern times,  aught has largely fallen into disuse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Barack Obama</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/barack-obama/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/barack-obama/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn English by filling in the
gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barack Obama and _ family are enjoying a holiday in
Indonesia, spending time white-water rafting _ visiting temples. He
arrived _ his wife and two daughters on the island of Bali before
visiting an ancient Buddhist temple _ Java on Wednesday. Mr Obama is a
popular figure in Indonesia where his holiday _ received saturation
press coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with, in, has, his, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and, his, with, in, has&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has, in, with, his, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;his, has, in, with, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;his, and, with, in, has&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;his, and, in, has, with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Basic grammar and punctuation.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/basic-grammar-punctuation/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/basic-grammar-punctuation/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Grammar is the sound, structure, and meaning system of language. All languages have grammar, and each language has its own grammar. People who speak the same language are able to communicate because they intuitively know the grammar system of that language—that is, the rules of making meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts of Speech&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Nouns - used to name a person, an animal, a place, a thing or an idea.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Pronouns - used to take the place of a previously named noun.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Verbs - words that express an action.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Adjectives - words that describe or modify the meaning of a noun or pronoun.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Adverbs - words that describe or modify a verb, adjective or adverb.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Articles - short words that precede nouns.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Conjunctions - words that link other words to form a sentence.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Prepositions - words that work together with nouns or pronouns to form a phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentence Structure&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Sentences - can be as long as a paragraph or as short as one word.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Phrases - two or more words that form a grammatically related part of a sentence.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Clauses - a group of words containing a subject and a predicate.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Agreement - words that logically correspond with one another in terms of person, number or gender.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Parallelism - also known as parallel structure or parallel construction, is a balance within one or more sentences of similar phrases or clauses that have the same grammatical structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Punctuation&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Apostrophes - used to indicate the possessive case.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Capitalisation - proper nouns and most proper adjectives begin with a capital letter.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Colons - indicate that what follows explains and forms a break before a main clause.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Commas - separates words in a list or series.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Dashes - can be used in the same way as commas, colons or parentheses.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Ellipses - indicate the omission of words in a sentence.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Exclamation Marks - add emphasis or to indicate surprise, disbelief and annoyance.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Hyphens - used in compound constructions to avoid ambiguity.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Italics - used to differentiate words from the surrounding text.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Numbers - newspapers and magazines use figures for numbers greater than nine.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Parentheses - separates words or parts of a sentence that are incidental to the main topic.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Periods - used to conclude a sentence and between initials.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Question Marks - used to conclude a direct question.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Quotation Marks - used to indicate dialogue, identifying direct speech.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Semicolons - indicate a break between a complete clause and a related clause.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Collective nouns.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/collective-nouns-and-consistency/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/collective-nouns-and-consistency/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;In American English, most collective nouns take singular verbs, except when a sentence emphasises the individuals in the group, not the group as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In British English, collective nouns are more often treated as plurals that take plural verbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A collective noun names a group of individuals or things with a singular form. Examples of collective nouns are: faculty, herd, team. There are collective nouns for people, animals, objects, and concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of a singular or plural verb depends on the context of the sentence. If one is referring to the whole group as a single entity, then the singular verb is best:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school board has called a special session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a group noun is used with a singular determiner (e.g., a/an, each, every, this, that), singular verbs and pronouns are normal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team is away this weekend; they have a good chance of winning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other contexts where the plural verb is more natural:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My family are always fighting among themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the individuals in the collection or group receive the emphasis, the plural verb is acceptable. Generally, however, in American English, collective nouns take singular verbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a sentence like &amp;lsquo;Lions are a dangerous animal.&amp;rsquo;, the collective noun lions is singular. But consider &amp;lsquo;Lions are dangerous animals&amp;rsquo;. In that sentence, lions is plural because it refers to the members rather than to an individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some sentences could go either way and often it&amp;rsquo;s a judgment call whether to make lions singular or plural. Although collective nouns can be singular or plural, depending on context, keeping them singular is the preference of many writers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Commas with participial phrases.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/commas-participial-phrases/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/commas-participial-phrases/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need a comma with participial phrases, and sometimes you don’t. A participle is a word formed from a verb which can be used as an adjective. The two types of participles are the present participle (ending ing) and the past participle (usually ending -ed, -d, -t, -en, or -n).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Making me laugh” is a participial phrase because it starts with the participle “making.” Participial phrases can appear anywhere in a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with sentence-ending participial phrases is that writers often add such a phrase as an afterthought, and they often omit a needed comma. You can’t just stick on a phrase somewhere without paying attention to punctuation. If a participial phrase comes at the end of a sentence, use a comma — unless the phrase is restrictive. When your sentence ends with a participial phrase, you need to decide if the phrase contains extra information or crucial information. If it’s added information, add a comma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A restrictive clause is just part of a sentence that you can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of because it specifically restricts some other part of the sentence. You could say, “The boy who fell off his bike wished he had stayed home.”  Here, the “who” clause is restrictive: It defines which particular boy wished he had stayed home, so you can’t delete the clause, nor do you use commas around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nonrestrictive clause is something that can be left off without changing the meaning of the sentence. You can think of a nonrestrictive clause as simply additional information. Such clauses are usually surrounded by, or preceded by, commas. An example is the “which” clause in this sentence: “The lake, which lies twenty miles from the capital, is famous for its boating festival.” The “which” clause is surrounded by commas. It contains additional information that is not necessary to understand the sentence, so you can delete the clause if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be easy to get confused about restrictive and nonrestrictive elements, so remember this: If it’s extra information, use extra commas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Compound sentences</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/compound-sentences/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/compound-sentences/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A compound sentence has at least two independent clauses that have related ideas. Conjunctions have one job, to connect. They join words, phrases, or clauses together to clarify what the writer is saying. Their presence provides smooth transitions from one idea to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A conjunctive adverb can join two main clauses. In this situation, the conjunctive adverb behaves like a coordinating conjunction, connecting two complete ideas. Notice, however, that you need a semicolon, not a comma, to connect the two clauses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose the appropriate conjunctive adverb:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;otherwise moreover then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dark skies and distant thunder dissuaded Mary from her early morning run; __, she had twenty essays to correct for her afternoon class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen&amp;rsquo;s apartment complex does not allow dogs over 13Kg; __, she would have bought the gangly Great Dane puppy playing in the pet store window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cat ate a bowlful of tuna; __, to the squirrels&amp;rsquo; delight, the fat feline fell asleep in the rocking chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Conjunctions - as, because, because of.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/conjunctions/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/conjunctions/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;As and because are conjunctions. As and because introduce subordinate clauses. They connect the result of something with its reason. Because is more common than as.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He spoke quietly because he did not want Susan to hear.&lt;br&gt;
Everyone left early because Robert and Susan had to catch an early flight in the morning.&lt;br&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;ll come over on Saturday because Tom has to work on Friday.&lt;br&gt;
Are you feeling ill because you ate too much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often put the because-clause at the beginning of a sentence. We use a comma after the because-clause:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because walking is something we do every day, we rarely think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Because of&amp;rsquo; is a two-word preposition meaning &amp;lsquo;as a result of&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the rain, the cricket match was postponed.&lt;br&gt;
There were so many people in the store because of the summer sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often use as when we want to focus more on the result than the reason. As is more formal than because.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope they&amp;rsquo;ve decided to come as I wanted to hear about their Africa trip.&lt;br&gt;
As you all know each other, there&amp;rsquo;s no need for introductions. We&amp;rsquo;ll get straight down to business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While and The Subordinate Clause&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subordinating conjunctions are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after, although, as, as if, because, before, even if, even though, if, if only, rather than, since, that, though, unless, until, when, where, whereas, wherever, whether, which, and while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word; while; creates a subordinating conjunction when it begins a sentence. The key is that it instantly makes the clause dependent whether it is independent or dependent, so you will have to follow it with an independent clause.
When you attach a subordinate clause in front of a main clause, use a comma, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subordinate Clause, Main Clause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Mary slept on the sofa in front of the television, Rover the family dog, gnawed on the leg of the coffee table.&lt;br&gt;
While the snow just kept coming down, it was not accumulating as quickly as you would think.&lt;br&gt;
While I did my homework, my father was washing the car.&lt;br&gt;
While my parents drank coffee, my brother was watching TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;While&amp;rsquo; is the subordinate conjunction that introduces the subordinate clause, and because it appears at the beginning of the complete sentence, it is separated from the main clause with a comma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Courtesy in your writing.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/courtesy/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/courtesy/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Courtesy in your writing and grammatical etiquette, put yourself last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between &amp;ldquo;I and my friends&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;my friends and I&amp;rdquo; is purely a matter of courtesy - they are both grammatically correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter though, is more common-place, considered more polite, and seems to flow better. In formal standard written English, subjects of verbs must be in subjective form, conjoined or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends and I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Smith and I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My husband and I.
The King and I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends and I are going on holiday to Bali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary and I are having dinner tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is correct? My friends and I or my friends and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends and I - when it is the subject of the sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends and me - when it is the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sister and I are going to meet David today. (as subject)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David is going to meet my sister and me today. (as object)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents took my brother and me to Bali every year when we were young.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Dependent and dependant.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/dependent-and-dependant/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/dependent-and-dependant/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Dependent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Australian and British English, &amp;lsquo;dependent&amp;rsquo; is an adjective and means to depend on something else for help or support, subordinate or reliant upon. Examples of using &amp;lsquo;dependent&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of the house renovation is dependent on the budgetary targets being met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be going camping on the weekend, but this is dependent on the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Australian and British English, &amp;lsquo;dependant&amp;rsquo; is a noun and means a person or servant who depends on another for support. Examples of &amp;lsquo;dependant&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to list the children as dependants on my application form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All siblings and their dependants will be invited to the wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easier to think of &amp;lsquo;dependant&amp;rsquo; as being a person and &amp;lsquo;dependent&amp;rsquo; as describing a reliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In American English, there is no difference in spellings; &amp;lsquo;dependent&amp;rsquo; is used to cover both circumstances. However, you may see &amp;lsquo;dependant&amp;rsquo; used in some circumstances, this is acceptable use and would follow the same definitions as Australian and British English.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>EOFY</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/eofy/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/eofy/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;EOFY, the end of the financial year, 30th of June. In some countries it is the 1st of January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am busy finalising my accounts for the year. What are you going to do today?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Especially and specially are adverbs.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/especially-or-specially/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/especially-or-specially/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Especially means &amp;lsquo;particularly&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;above all&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She loves flowers, especially roses.&lt;br&gt;
I am especially grateful to all my family and friends who supported me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not: Especially I am&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use specially to talk about the specific purpose of something:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kitchen was specially designed to make it easy for a disabled person to use.&lt;br&gt;
He has his shirts made specially for him by a tailor in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially can also be used to mean &amp;lsquo;for a particular purpose&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought these (e)specially for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Everyday and every day.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/everyday-every-day/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/everyday-every-day/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyday is an adjective we use to describe something that’s seen or used every day. It means &amp;lsquo;ordinary&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;typical&amp;rsquo;. Every day is a phrase that simply means &amp;lsquo;each day&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These shoes are great for everyday wear.
You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t wear an everyday outfit to the wedding.
Don&amp;rsquo;t use the everyday dishes – it’s a special occasion.
I go to the park every day.
She has a hamburger for lunch every day.
I have to work every day this week except Friday.
Every day I feel a little better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyday is a single word and is an adjective, so it&amp;rsquo;s the one that is used in front of a noun to describe something as normal or commonplace. Every day is an adjective (every) plus a noun (day), and it means each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compound words, like anytime and any time, sometimes don&amp;rsquo;t have the same meaning as the individual words they comprise. Everyday and every day are like that, everyday (with no space) doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean the same thing as every day (with a space). In speech, however, they do sound the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can you tell easily which one to use? By replacing the &amp;lsquo;day&amp;rsquo; section with an actual day of the week, you will find out whether it is right. Let&amp;rsquo;s take this phrase: This is available all day everyday/every day. So, now, replace the &amp;lsquo;day&amp;rsquo; section with an actual day of the week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is available all day everyday. [all one word] This becomes: This is available all day everyMonday. [all one word] WRONG&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is available all day every day. This becomes: This is available all day every Monday. [two words] RIGHT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you would not write &amp;lsquo;every Monday&amp;rsquo; as one word in this example, so you will not write &amp;lsquo;every day; as one word either!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Food or foods?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/food-or-foods/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/food-or-foods/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first rules that students learn is that uncountable nouns can&amp;rsquo;t be used in the plural form. As you continue studying, you start seeing foods and fruits, is the rule wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some nouns that are both countable and uncountable nouns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In English, there are countable nouns (also known as count nouns) and uncountable nouns (also known as non-count nouns).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countable nouns are things that you can count:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One plant, two plants, three plants.&lt;br&gt;
One tooth, two teeth, three teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncountable nouns are things that you cannot count, or nouns that represent a group:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;information&lt;br&gt;
advice&lt;br&gt;
homework&lt;br&gt;
furniture&lt;br&gt;
clothing&lt;br&gt;
research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncountable nouns have no plural form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food or foods?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food is an uncountable noun. You can&amp;rsquo;t count one food or two foods. Use food as an uncountable noun when you are talking about food in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People need to eat food to survive.&lt;br&gt;
I can’t eat all this food!&lt;br&gt;
Eating spicy food can help you live longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you can also talk about specific kinds of food, and this is where you can sometimes use foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese food and Italian food are examples of foreign foods.&lt;br&gt;
The doctor said you need to eat more fruits, vegetables, and other healthy foods.&lt;br&gt;
I have intolerances to a lot of foods. I can&amp;rsquo;t eat wheat, dairy, soy, almonds and a lot of other things!&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m having frozen food for dinner tonight. I looked in the freezer and I found all kinds of frozen foods, so I took one and put in the microwave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not sure if you should use food or foods, use food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the plural of fish?&lt;br&gt;
Is fish a countable or uncountable noun?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Gender-neutral pronouns</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/gender-neutral-pronouns/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/gender-neutral-pronouns/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Gender-neutral pronouns, them, their or they. English lacks an uncontroversial pronoun that lets you talk about a person of a generic or unknown gender, known as an &amp;lsquo;epicene&amp;rsquo; pronoun, from the Greek for &amp;lsquo;common to all&amp;rsquo; (genders).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &amp;lsquo;they&amp;rsquo; to refer to a general single individual when the gender is not known, and either &amp;lsquo;he&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;she&amp;rsquo; when the gender is known. If it&amp;rsquo;s a group of people, either all of the same gender or of mixed gender, use &amp;lsquo;they.&amp;rsquo; He or she quickly becomes wearisome on repetition. Alternating he and she is distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They/them/their is acceptable in limited cases as a singular and-or gender-neutral pronoun, when alternative wording is overly awkward or clumsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efforts to use their instead of his are modern political correctness running roughshod over grammatical good sense. Their can do double-duty just as your can for both singular and plural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The singular, epicene &amp;lsquo;they&amp;rsquo; has not just modern gender equality but seven centuries of the finest literary tradition on its side. Supporters of the epicene &amp;lsquo;they&amp;rsquo; argue that it is high time this was accepted, in a world aware of sex discrimination. But this is unlikely to convince traditionalists. A better argument is that the singular &amp;lsquo;they&amp;rsquo; is hardly a new political invention, for hundreds of years &amp;lsquo;they&amp;rsquo; has been regularly used for single individuals (including in classic literature).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone answered, but they spoke so quietly no one could make out the words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know who they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The student didn&amp;rsquo;t want to confess that it was they that were at fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teacher was not guilty, were they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither knows the answer, do they?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Gerund - infinitive</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/gerund/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/gerund/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A gerund is a traditional grammatical term for a verb form that ends in -ing and functions as a noun. A gerund (also known as an -ing form) with its objects, complements, and modifiers is called a gerund phrase, or simply a noun phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the Gerund or the Infinitive after the following verbs. There are two possible structures after these verbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerund: verb + -ing
Infinitive: verb + person + to-infinitive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some verbs take &amp;lsquo;to-infinitive&amp;rsquo; clauses and some take an &amp;lsquo;-ing&amp;rsquo; clause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, &amp;lsquo;hope&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;expect&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;learn&amp;rsquo; normally take &amp;lsquo;to-infinitive&amp;rsquo;:
&amp;lsquo;I learnt to swim in Australia last summer.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I expect to get high marks in this exam because I put in a lot of work for it.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I hope to recover in time for my business trip to Indonesia in July.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some verbs, e.g. &amp;lsquo;tell&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;advise&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;ask&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;to-infinitive&amp;rsquo; follows the object:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;We asked them to show us the way.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;He advised me to drive more slowly through the village.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I told him to be quiet.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other verbs, such as &amp;lsquo;enjoy&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;finish&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;admit&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;mind&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;feel like&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;can&amp;rsquo;t help&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;look forward to&amp;rsquo; take an &amp;lsquo;-ing&amp;rsquo; clause:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t help feeling that it&amp;rsquo;s going to rain before we get home.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I feel like stopping work now and coming back to it later. &#39;
&amp;lsquo;Do you mind not talking in here? Speaking is not allowed in the library.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;He admitted taking the bribe and leaking the documents to the press.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I always enjoy listening to Mozart whenever I&amp;rsquo;m feeling stressed.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;She finished cleaning the floor and then she dusted the room.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I look forward to hearing from you.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Prevent&amp;rsquo; is followed by an object + (from) + an &amp;lsquo;-ing&amp;rsquo; clause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I prevented him from stealing the painting.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some verbs such as begin, start, like, love, hate, continue, cease can take either a &amp;lsquo;to-infinitive&amp;rsquo; or an &amp;lsquo;-ing&amp;rsquo; clause and there is usually little or no difference in meaning between them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I like to read in the bath.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I like reading in the bath.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I continued to work till Mary came in and then we had supper.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I continued working till Mary came in and then we had supper.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the meaning does change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I stopped smoking when I married Susan.&amp;rsquo; = I gave up smoking when I married Susan.
&amp;lsquo;I stopped to smoke a cigarette.&amp;rsquo; = I stopped what I was doing in order to smoke a cigarette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &amp;lsquo;decide to&amp;rsquo; would be the norm:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;She has decided to model clothes for both the Spanish and the French fashion houses this year.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Decide&amp;rsquo; + &amp;lsquo;-ing&amp;rsquo; would only be possible if the &amp;lsquo;-ing&amp;rsquo; form functions as a gerund, as in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;She decided modelling was the best career for her.&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;I decided smoking was bad for me.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Get and Got</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/get-and-got/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/get-and-got/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Get is normal English, and there&amp;rsquo;s no need to substitute another word for it. However, if you&amp;rsquo;re writing a very formal paper, you can use more formal words such as receive, purchase, and obtain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have got and have mean the same. Have got is more informal. We use have (got) here to refer to both verbs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got a terrible pain in my back.&lt;br&gt;
I have a terrible pain in my back. (more formal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They haven&amp;rsquo;t got a car.&lt;br&gt;
They don&amp;rsquo;t have a car. (more formal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use have (got) to talk about possession, relationships, characteristics and illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s got two cats and a dog.&lt;br&gt;
She has two cats and a dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you got a drill?&lt;br&gt;
Do you have a drill? (more formal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many brothers have you got?&lt;br&gt;
How many brothers do you have? (more formal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s got a new boyfriend.&lt;br&gt;
She has a new boyfriend. (more formal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s got a delightful voice.&lt;br&gt;
She has a delightful voice. (more formal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s got 153 calories and 45g of carbohydrates.&lt;br&gt;
It has 153 calories and 45g of carbohydrates. (more formal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never had the measles.&lt;br&gt;
She&amp;rsquo;s got a headache.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Going to, about to, or will.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/going-to-about-or-will/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/going-to-about-or-will/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Going to simply means intending to do something, at some point in the future. It can also imply (depending on context and speaker&amp;rsquo;s tone of voice) that the intention is to do it &amp;lsquo;sometime… never&amp;rsquo;, i.e. the intention is very weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About to adds more immediacy to the intention of doing that thing; &amp;lsquo;on the brink of doing something&amp;rsquo;. Or it can mean that the intention was interrupted (and possibly not fulfilled) by something else. It is often prefaced with just, which amplifies the immediacy.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to have my dinner and watch TV for a while.&lt;br&gt;
(Actually I am not very hungry and I can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered cooking, and there is not much on TV, so I might just go to bed early instead.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am (just) about to have my dinner and watch TV for a while.&lt;br&gt;
(I must hurry and cook something quickly so that I can watch my favourite TV drama series which starts at 9:30PM.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are making a future prediction based on evidence in the present situation, use &amp;lsquo;going to&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a cloud in the sky. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be another warm day.&lt;br&gt;
Look at the queue. We&amp;rsquo;re not going to get in for hours.&lt;br&gt;
The traffic is terrible. We&amp;rsquo;re going to miss our flight.&lt;br&gt;
Be careful! You&amp;rsquo;re going to spill your coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we want to talk about future facts or things we believe to be true about the future, we use &amp;lsquo;will&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister will serve for four years.&lt;br&gt;
The teacher won&amp;rsquo;t be very happy.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ll like him.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m certain she&amp;rsquo;ll do a good job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are not so certain about the future, we use &amp;lsquo;will&amp;rsquo; with expressions such as &amp;lsquo;probably&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;possibly&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;I think&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;I hope&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll visit me in my office one day.&lt;br&gt;
He&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a great success.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll possibly come but I may not get back in time.&lt;br&gt;
I think we&amp;rsquo;ll get on well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment of making a decision, use &amp;lsquo;will&amp;rsquo;. Once you have made the decision, talk about it using &amp;lsquo;going to&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll call Mary to let her know. Susan, I need Mary&amp;rsquo;s number. I&amp;rsquo;m going to call her about the meeting.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll come and have a drink with you but I must let George know. George, I&amp;rsquo;m going to have a drink with Robert.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Handwritten Letters</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/handwritten/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/handwritten/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Not so long ago we would contact someone by writing a handwritten letter. We would choose a  clean sheet of white paper and starting at the top left-hand corner carefully enter the recipients name and address, conscious of the need for accuracy and neatness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old ways are hard. They’re time consuming. And how we spend our time is a language unto itself—a letter written by hand creates a much different set of feelings than a simple email.
The value of the handwritten letter lies within this language of time and care. Writing to someone, taking the time to craft each letter, to buy a stamp, to select an envelope, to travel to the post office—none of this goes unnoticed. A letter, before the content is even read, has already said, “I care about you. You’re someone special.” And that is a message that all enjoy.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost nobody receives handwritten letters anymore, but how it changes our life when we receive one. We look at the return address, and our heart beats faster. What does this person have to say to me that’s so special that they sent me a letter instead of an email, a text message, or a phone call? We open the envelope, and we are eager to read. It’s from someone who has already demonstrated that he or she has dedicated time to contacting us; someone who has thought about us and has taken up pen and paper to go through the trouble of sharing a moment of their life with us.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A handwritten letter today can awaken in us more powerful emotions than a treasure chest on a desert island; it can inspire and evoke memories, a feeling of happiness, the yearning for a loved one who is far away.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You are important to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Has or is</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/has-or-is/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/has-or-is/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;When has or is comes before a past participle (been, done, gone, made, etc.), we have to understand the meaning from the context of the whole sentence. Sometimes this is easy, other times more difficult:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter has gone to school.&lt;br&gt;
Peter is going to school as soon as he finishes his breakfast.&lt;br&gt;
It has been 10 years since I saw her.&lt;br&gt;
Coca-Cola is the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular soft drink, it is sold everywhere.&lt;br&gt;
Peter is asleep again.&lt;br&gt;
The coffee has gone. Peter has drunk it all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Have had or has had.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/has-had-have-had/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/has-had-have-had/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;You use has, have, and had if you do not care about the time and if the time is not definite. You use &amp;lsquo;had had&amp;rsquo; if something has been done a long time ago, not recently. But if some thing has been done recently, then you can use &amp;lsquo;have had&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;has had&amp;rsquo; depending on the pronoun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had had my breakfast earlier this morning. (past perfect tense)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you have had your breakfast too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had an interesting time reading all the comments this morning. (present perfect tense)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you have had an interesting time as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present perfect form of have is have had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Have you had your breakfast?&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;I have had a cup of coffee, but I haven’t had anything to eat yet.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any rest since early this morning. The past perfect form of have is had had (had + past participle form of have).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past perfect tense is used when we are talking about the past and want to refer back to an earlier past time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She felt great after she had had a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They dismissed him before he had had a chance to apologise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Have to, has to, had to.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/have-to-has-to-had-to/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/have-to-has-to-had-to/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Have to is often grouped with modal auxiliary verbs for convenience, but in fact it is not a modal verb. It is not even an auxiliary verb. In the have to structure, &amp;lsquo;have&amp;rsquo; is a main verb. The structure is: subject + auxiliary verb + have + infinitive (with to).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use of Have to&lt;br&gt;
In general, have to expresses impersonal obligation. The subject of have to is obliged or forced to act by a separate, external power (for example, the Law or school rules). Have to is objective. Look at these examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In France, you have to drive on the right.&lt;br&gt;
In England, most schoolchildren have to wear a uniform.&lt;br&gt;
John has to wear a tie at work.&lt;br&gt;
I had to study hard to pass my exams, but it was worth the effort as now I have a good job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each of the above cases, the obligation is not the subject&amp;rsquo;s opinion or idea. The obligation is imposed from outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can use have to in all tenses, and also with modal auxiliaries. We conjugate it just like any other main verb.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>How to begin a conversation.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/courtesy-good-manners-writing/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/courtesy-good-manners-writing/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of you are here because you want to be able to understand and communicate with English speakers in everyday situations. It is important therefore that you know how to begin a conversation, email or letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some phrases that might be commonly used in your culture may be offensive or disrespectful to a native speaker, who is probably from a totally different culture, and vice versa. They may be so offensive that your message will be ignored or even deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you negotiate this minefield of cultural differences in your writing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the only answer is to use plain, normal English and totally avoid all forms of slang expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid slang expressions such as:&lt;br&gt;
Bro, brother, dude, bule, mister, hey, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know the name of the person you are writing to:&lt;br&gt;
Dear President Jokowi,&lt;br&gt;
Dear Mr McKean,&lt;br&gt;
Dear Andrew,&lt;br&gt;
Hello Andrew,&lt;br&gt;
Hi Andrew,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name of the person:&lt;br&gt;
Dear Sir,&lt;br&gt;
Dear Madam,&lt;br&gt;
Hello,&lt;br&gt;
Hi,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that &amp;lsquo;sir&amp;rsquo; is only capitalised if it is used to start a sentence or as part of a salutation and only when preceded by &amp;lsquo;Dear&amp;rsquo;. Except if you are referring to a person who has been knighted by the Queen.&lt;br&gt;
These are incorrect:&lt;br&gt;
Hello Sir,&lt;br&gt;
Hi Sir,&lt;br&gt;
Hello Sir Andrew, (I have not been knighted by the Queen, at least not yet.)&lt;br&gt;
These are correct:&lt;br&gt;
Sir, thank you for your interesting lesson.&lt;br&gt;
Thank you sir, for the interesting lesson.&lt;br&gt;
In 1997, Sir Paul McCartney was knighted for services to music.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>IELTS interview test tips.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/ielts-interview-test-tips/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/ielts-interview-test-tips/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Develop what you say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you are asked what seems like a yes - no question, you are expected to say more. The IELTS interview gives you roughly 10 to 15 minutes of time to display your English speaking skills to the examiner. If you give one-word or very short answers to questions you are not giving the examiner much with which to assess you. You are expected to say more than a simple &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;no&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should try to develop what you say by giving reasons, opinions or describing something in more detail, show off your English skills.&lt;br&gt;
A good tip for candidates is to look for signals from the examiner. Often you can see from the examiner&amp;rsquo;s facial expression or manner if you have said enough or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get over-emotional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview situation it&amp;rsquo;s always good to express yourself and to convey your feelings, however there is a limit. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to put yourself in a situation that causes you to become over-emotional and perhaps lose control as this could jeopardise the success of your whole interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid this, think about the kind of things that you may be asked about in an interview that could cause you to get emotional, a pet that died recently, an exam you failed, an argument you had with a friend. By thinking about them in advance you can mentally prepare yourself to talk about them, or our best advice would be to try to avoid talking on these sensitive subjects altogether and wherever possible answer the question using a different example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t memorise answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s common for interviewees to prepare answers in advance but there are things that you should avoid doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent you can predict the kind of topics that you might be asked to talk about in the IELTS interview. This means that it is quite common for interviewees to prepare answers in advance and learn them by heart. Then, in the interview if the topic comes up they will regurgitate (verb; repeat after memorisation) their answer, whether it answers the question or not. There are several problems with this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, it is usually very clear that an answer has been memorised as it sounds very unnatural to the examiner. Examiners have a lot of experience interviewing people and they can easily see when something isn’t quite right. If they suspect that the answer has been memorised they will probably interrupt your answer and move on to another question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, if you have memorised an answer it is very unlikely that it will actually answer the question directly and this will be another signal to the examiner that something isn&amp;rsquo;t quite right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, you should avoid trying to memorise answers, but you can still prepare for the interview by thinking about possible topics and making sure you have the vocabulary and language to talk about the topics in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a job interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IELTS interview is different from a job interview. Be sure to showcase your English ability, not your job qualification. Are job interviews the same as IELTS interviews? The answer is, in some ways they are and in others they are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are they the same?&lt;br&gt;
In a job interview and an IELTS interview you are asked questions and based on your answers you are judged by another person. In both you are trying to create a good impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are they different?&lt;br&gt;
In a job interview you are trying to showcase your experience, your qualifications and your skills and expertise that are relevant for the job you are applying for. In contrast, in an IELTS interview you are only showcasing your level of spoken English and it is this that the examiner will judge you on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an IELTS interview you do not need to sell yourself in terms of your job qualifications or experience, you simply need to demonstrate to the examiner your competence in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be better to express a negative opinion if that gives you more to say. What would you do if you were asked in an interview to talk about how you feel about your hometown if in fact you really disliked living there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people might think that by being truthful in this situation and giving a negative answer that this would not be the right thing to do and instead you should lie and talk about how you love living there to give a more positive sounding answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, truthfulness is not important and neither is giving a negative opinion of something. The important thing is that you have something to express. If you have more to say by being truthful, even if it is expressing a negative opinion, then that is what you should talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be much better to say &amp;lsquo;Actually I don&amp;rsquo;t really like my hometown&amp;rsquo; and follow it up with your reasons for disliking it than to say &amp;lsquo;I like my hometown&amp;rsquo; and then struggle to find anything to say.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>IELTS writing test.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/writing-an-ielts-essay/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/writing-an-ielts-essay/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;If your ultimate goal is to pass the IELTS writing test then you probably already know that essay writing is critical to your overall score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do we write an essay of at least 250 words?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to identify and understand the topic, viewpoint and specific question clearly because this will influence how you structure your essay. The specific question indicates that you should write one of the following types of essays:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problem-Solution: Write about the causes of a problem and suggest possible solutions.&lt;br&gt;
Argument: Asks you to give an opinion on an issue and support that opinion throughout the entire essay.&lt;br&gt;
Discussion: Asks you to consider an issue from different points of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An essay can be simplified as three main parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction.&lt;br&gt;
The body.&lt;br&gt;
The conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction should be one or two sentences. It needs to include the important information found in the question and be written in your own words. The three parts of an introduction are topic, viewpoint, and specific question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of the body is different depending on the type of essay you are writing. There are alternative structures for each essay type: Discussion, Argument, and Problem: Solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an IELTS essay there should be no more than five paragraphs in total, that means no more than three main body paragraphs. Body paragraphs are obviously very important and this is where you will gain most of your points in the marking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each essay type has its own structure but they have similar paragraph rules. One particular essay type &amp;lsquo;Discuss both views and give your own opinion&amp;rsquo; can also use three main body paragraphs, two to discuss the views and one to give your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main body paragraphs should have the following structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic Sentence&lt;br&gt;
Supporting Sentences&lt;br&gt;
Specific example&lt;br&gt;
State your opinion (only if the question asks for an opinion)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion is the last paragraph of your essay and is the final impression the examiner has of your writing. You should always summarise the main ideas that you have presented in your essay. In the conclusion of a discussion or argument essay, you should also give your viewpoint. Note that the use of time markers here is very important, they make your answer cohesive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>If&#39;s, but&#39;s, maybe&#39;s and possibly&#39;s</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/ifs-buts-maybes-possiblys/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/ifs-buts-maybes-possiblys/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;If a plural word is being quoted in a sentence, it is often written with an apostrophe, though the apostrophe can be omitted if there would be confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are too many if&amp;rsquo;s, but&amp;rsquo;s, maybe&amp;rsquo;s and possibly&amp;rsquo;s in this proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can argue forever against the if&amp;rsquo;s, but&amp;rsquo;s and maybe&amp;rsquo;s, and undoubtedly we need to work on improving our conversion rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a few sentences containing if, but, maybe and possibly. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were a rich man then maybe you would marry me, but how could I possibly know what you are thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Immigrate and emigrate.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/immigrate-and-emigrate/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/immigrate-and-emigrate/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;My father immigrated from Scotland to Australia when he was a young man. A few years ago I thought of emigrating from Australia to the USA as I was offered a job in Minnesota, but I decided not to go as the weather is so cold there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immigrate means to enter a new country with the purpose of staying there. Immigrate focuses on the point of arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emigrate means to leave one country and settle in another.&lt;br&gt;
Emigrate focuses on the point of departure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you planning to emigrate?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>In time or on time.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/in-time-or-on-time/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/in-time-or-on-time/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the bus stop on time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;In time&amp;rsquo; usually has an implicit &amp;lsquo;for (some event)&amp;rsquo;, whereas &amp;lsquo;on time&amp;rsquo; means &amp;lsquo;before some deadline&amp;rsquo;. The &amp;lsquo;event&amp;rsquo; could be a deadline, but in that case &amp;lsquo;on time&amp;rsquo; is much more common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got there in time &amp;lsquo;meaning&amp;rsquo; in time for some event which is assumed to be known&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got there in time for the express bus to the city.&lt;br&gt;
I delivered the coffee in time for her to drink it before the exam.&lt;br&gt;
I got to the airport in time (for)/(to catch) the last flight to Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got there on time, meaning &amp;lsquo;before the deadline&amp;rsquo;, which may be known to the hearer, but does not need to be, because the phrase itself implies a deadline as opposed to some other event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The express train is scheduled to arrive on time at 10:10AM.&lt;br&gt;
Despite the bad weather, the project was completed on time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Is and are.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/is-and-are/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/is-and-are/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;When deciding which of the helping verbs &amp;lsquo;is&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;are&amp;rsquo; to use look at whether the noun is plural or singular. If the noun is singular use &amp;lsquo;is&amp;rsquo;, if it is plural or there is more than one noun use &amp;lsquo;are&amp;rsquo;.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dress is related to the body in the same way that bangles are related to the wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Is SMS texting ruining English?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/sms/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/sms/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;My smmr hols wr CWOT. B4, we used 2go2 NY 2C my bro, his GF &amp;amp; thr 3 :-@ kids FTF. ILNY, it&amp;rsquo;s a gr8 plc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great English language, with its power to move and to anger, to frighten and to perplex, to amuse and to inspire, to change the course of history, is being debased into some moronic machine code by this mind-numbing new form of communication called SMS texting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What has happened to the passion and power of a well written letter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of these abbreviations allows the user to avoid having to spell correctly and masks their ignorance of the language and its usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have your say, what do you think? Am I wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Is SMS texting ruining our writing skills?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/texting/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/texting/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Handwritten letters are gone. Now love comes packaged in misspelled texts written by a clumsy pair of thumbs. The age of handwritten letters, making their perishable crawl across the country to an awaiting lover’s mailbox, is over. In their place are heartfelt missives delivered instantly and electronically — a tender, “Luv u,” or the simple yet ethereal winky face, and violations of standard written English, such as using “gonna” in place of “going to” or several exclamation points at a time instead of just one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your written English is so important for your future, and a pressing question emerges from this emotional wreckage: In migrating our lives to texting, does our grammar suffer to expediency?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have your say.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Learning English</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/learning-english/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/learning-english/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Write a few sentences about learning English and how you are progressing with your English studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a person decides to learn English, they are not merely absorbing the linguistics of the language, but everything to do with English and English speaking countries. Language is culture. Language is the soul of the country and the people who speak it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a few sentences and I will correct your grammar, spelling and punctuation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Linking words, although, despite.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/in-spite-of/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/in-spite-of/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;We use linking words to join ideas together. Sometimes we want to link two ideas that are different from each other or we want to link one idea to another one which is surprising or unexpected. We can use linking words like although, despite, and however to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although&lt;br&gt;
We can use although at the beginning or in the middle of a sentence. It is used in front of a clause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the weather is cool, I love hiking in the mountains.&lt;br&gt;
I love Sydney, although the weather is often very hot and humid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite / in spite of&lt;br&gt;
We use despite or in spite of before a noun or a gerund. It can also go in the middle or at the beginning of a sentence. Despite and in spite of mean exactly the same thing. If you want to use despite or in spite of before a clause, you need to add the fact that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Sydney despite the very hot and humid weather.&lt;br&gt;
I love Sydney in spite of the very hot and humid weather.&lt;br&gt;
Despite the very hot and humid weather, I love Sydney.&lt;br&gt;
In spite of the very hot and humid weather, I love Sydney.&lt;br&gt;
Despite the fact that the weather is very hot and humid, I love Sydney.&lt;br&gt;
In spite of the fact that the weather is very hot and humid, I love Sydney.&lt;br&gt;
I love Sydney despite the fact that the weather is very hot and humid.&lt;br&gt;
I love Sydney in spite of the fact that the weather is very hot and humid.&lt;br&gt;
In spite of not meeting all the requirements, he applied for the job.&lt;br&gt;
Despite the fact that he didnt meet all the requirements, he decided to apply for the job.&lt;br&gt;
In spite of the fact that he didnt meet all the requirements, he decided to apply for the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However&lt;br&gt;
We use although and despite / in spite of to connect two clauses in the same sentence. On the other hand, however isnt used to connect two clauses. Instead, we usually put the two ideas in two separate sentences. We put however in the second sentence, and we can put it at the beginning, at the end, or after the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Sydney. However, the weather is very hot and humid.&lt;br&gt;
I love Sydney. The weather, however, is very hot and humid.&lt;br&gt;
I love Sydney. The weather is very hot and humid, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a few sentences using however, despite and although. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is Sunday and a day of rest, I am going to mow my lawns, despite the fact that the noise might disturb my neighbours. It is the only spare time I have available and I am hoping the neighbours will go out for the day. The mower noise, however, might not be that annoying after all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Look or looks</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/looks/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/looks/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Wearing makeup makes her look beautiful.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
She looks beautiful when she wears makeup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So long as the look is only one look, it is a look, not a looks. So long as the person is a single person, they have a look; they do not have looks unless their appearance changes. This does not include a change in clothes, in that case, you would say that there are multiple looks which a person wears, not that they themselves have multiple looks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The person is their body and their body has one look at any given time so they have one look until their body changes at which point they will have had multiple looks, but they can never have multiple looks at the same time; therefore, &amp;ldquo;She looks good&amp;rdquo; does not mean &amp;ldquo;she has good looks&amp;rdquo; but rather &amp;ldquo;The look that she is presently presenting is good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you mean to say something referencing all of the looks which she has ever had and has the possibility of presenting, you should say, &amp;ldquo;At any given time, she possesses multiple outfits capable of creating a plethora of appealing looks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Millennials</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/millennials/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/millennials/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The silent generation, baby boomers, Millennial, Generation X, Y or Z?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays every generation has a defining label, and a set of stereotypical attributes attached. There&amp;rsquo;s often quite a lot of confusion regarding which generational classification everyone technically falls into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are part of the silent generation are characterised as having been born from the mid-to-late 1920s until the early-to-mid 1940s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;baby boomers&amp;rdquo; refers to the drastic rise in birth rates that was noted following the end of World War II.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generation X (or Gen X) is the demographic cohort following the baby boomers and preceding the Millennials. Popular media typically use birth years around 1965 to 1980 to define Generation Xers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millennials are often arguably regarded as an “entitled” generation that’s “ruined” everything, from diamonds to sex. Millennials can give as good as they get, sometimes expressing their disappointment in the way in which previous generations have handled issues such as the housing crisis. The more technical term for millennials is generation Y, as they succeed generation X and precede generation Z. The starting birth years for millennials are 1980 or 1981.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generation Z are regarded as being a very tech-savvy generation, having been born during a time of fast-paced digital growth. They&amp;rsquo;ve also received a lot of attention in the media recently due to their strong views regarding politics and current affairs, especially in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many may flippantly describe all young people as millennials, the term is actually understood to refer to people who were born in the time period ranging from the early 1980s to the mid-1990s and early 2000s. However, as with generation Z, the exact start date for millennial birth years is a topic of debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to generation Z, millennials are defined as being particularly adept at using technology and social media platforms. They often receive a tough time in the press, with members of the generation being accused of &amp;ldquo;killing&amp;rdquo; a variety of things, such as beer, motorcycles and the notion of owning a home. Millennials may become outnumbered by generation Z in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Modal Verbs</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/modal-verbs/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/modal-verbs/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;English modal verbs are both important and subtle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subjunctive form is an attitude, not a defined structure. That is why we call it the subjunctive mood. The grammatical term subjunctive is not the same as the linguistic term subjunctive. As a general term, subjunctive is when there exists intention to describe an imaginary situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should have + past participle can mean something that would have been a good idea, but that you didn&amp;rsquo;t do it. It&amp;rsquo;s like giving advice about the past when you say it to someone else, or regretting what you did or didn&amp;rsquo;t do when you&amp;rsquo;re talking about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should have studied harder!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May have and might have mean the same thing in American English, and are nearly always interchangeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may have been taking a shower when you called.
I might have been taking a shower when you called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In British English we use may have and might have to show that something has possibly happened now or happened at some time in the past:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ten o&amp;rsquo;clock. They might have arrived now.
They may have arrived hours ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only may is used to communicate that something is permitted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one may enter without a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only might is used to talk about an unreal condition or situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were more experienced, you might have an easier time finding a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can have implies that someone has the opportunity to possess or do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary can have an ice cream cone when she gets home. George can have his friends over after school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could have + past participle means that something was possible in the past, or you had the ability to do something in the past, but that you didn&amp;rsquo;t do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could have loved you, had you too loved me. I could have stayed up late, but I decided to go to bed early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modal verb must has two past tense forms: had to and must have. Which form we use depends on whether we want to express obligation or if we want to say how certain we are about the probability of something happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He must have left the house by now; it&amp;rsquo;s nearly 11 o&amp;rsquo;clock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would have + past participle. (Part of the third conditional).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had had enough money, I would have bought a car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also use would have + past participle to talk about something you wanted to do but didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would have gone to the party, but I was really busy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>More about &#39;The Articles&#39;.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/more-about-the-articles/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/more-about-the-articles/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The articles a/an, the.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word a (which becomes an when the next word begins with a vowel a, e, i, o, u) is called the indefinite article because the noun it goes with is indefinite or general. The word the is known as the definite article and indicates a specific thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exceptions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use before unsounded &amp;lsquo;h&amp;rsquo;. Because the &amp;lsquo;h&amp;rsquo; hasn&amp;rsquo;t any phonetic representation and has no audible sound, the sound that follows the article is a vowel; consequently, &amp;lsquo;an&amp;rsquo; is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An honorable peace, an honest error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &amp;lsquo;u&amp;rsquo; makes the same sound as the &amp;lsquo;y&amp;rsquo; in &amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;o&amp;rsquo;; makes the same sound as &amp;lsquo;w&amp;rsquo;; in &amp;lsquo;won&amp;rsquo;; then &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo; is used. The word-initial &amp;lsquo;y&amp;rsquo;; sound (&amp;lsquo;unicorn&amp;rsquo;) is actually a glide [j] phonetically, which has consonantal properties; consequently, it is treated as a consonant, requiring &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A union, a united front, a unicorn, a used napkin, a US ship, a one-legged man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the gaps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He was _ honest man, who lived _ quiet life among _ villagers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marriage is _ sacred union between _ man and _ woman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;_ US President addressed _ UN and laid out _ vision for _ world filled with sovereign states which worked for _ betterment of their citizens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;President Trump&amp;rsquo;s speech was _ eloquent exposition of his &amp;lsquo;America First&amp;rsquo; doctrine but at _ same time contained some fulsome (and perhaps unexpected) praise for _ United Nations as _ body that can bring together sovereign states to tackle _ world&amp;rsquo;s problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Peer, pier, pear and pare.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/peer-pier-pear-pair-and-pare/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/peer-pier-pear-pair-and-pare/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A person of the same age, the same social position, or having the same abilities as other people in a group: Getting help from a peer is easier than asking a teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influence from members of one&amp;rsquo;s peer group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer (verb):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To look with difficulty or concentration at someone or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pier (Noun):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A platform on pillars projecting from the shore into the sea, typically incorporating entertainment arcades and places to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pear (noun):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sweet yellowish- or brownish-green edible fruit which is narrow at the stalk and wider towards the base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pair (noun):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A set of two things used together or regarded as a unit.&lt;br&gt;
an article consisting of two joined or corresponding parts not used separately.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;lsquo;a pair of jeans&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pair (verb):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put together or join to form a pair.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;lsquo;a cardigan paired with a matching skirt&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pare (verb):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trim (something) by cutting away its outer edges.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;lsquo;Carlo pared his thumbnails with his knife&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a sentence or two using peer, pier, pear, pair and pare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Position of Adjectives</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/adjectives/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/adjectives/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The order in which we use adjectives in a series is confusing for people learning English, including many native speakers. It takes a lot of practise with a language before this order becomes instinctive, because the order often seems quite arbitrary. There is, however, a pattern. You will find many exceptions, two common patterns are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observation, Size, Shape, Age, Colour, Origin, Material, Qualifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opinion, Size, Age, Shape, Colour, Origin, Material, Purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which pattern you choose depends on the context and syntax involved. Very few people have this skill and those that do often go on to become professional writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike adverbs, adjectives nearly always appear immediately before the noun or noun phrase that they modify. Sometimes they appear in a string of adjectives, and when they do, they appear in a set order according to category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observation, Size, Shape, Age, Colour, Origin, Material, Qualifier, Noun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A beautiful petite slender young black-haired Javanese selfless understanding woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adjectives belong to the same class, they become coordinated adjectives, and you put a comma between them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The delicious, expensive chocolates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rule for inserting the comma is if you could have inserted a conjunction — and or but — between the two adjectives, use a comma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using three or more coordinated adjectives don’t insert a comma between the last adjective and the noun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An expensive, gorgeous, and revealing dress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you add to these examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Practice or practise</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/practice-or-practise/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/practice-or-practise/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;In British English, practice is a noun or adjective, and practise is a verb. For example, we would say that a doctor with a private practice, practises privately. There is no such distinction in American English, where practice is both a noun and a verb, and practise is not used at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My doctor&amp;rsquo;s practice is in Sydney. (noun)&lt;br&gt;
I hit a practice shot at the golf course. (adjective)&lt;br&gt;
I must practise the piano more. (verb)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Prepositions</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/prepositions/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/prepositions/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;There are over 100 prepositions in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of common prepositions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;above, about, across, against, along, among, around, at, before, behind, below, beneath, beside, between, beyond, by, down, during, except, for, from, in, inside, into, like, near, of, off, on, since, to, toward, through, under, until, up, upon, with and within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even advanced learners of English find prepositions difficult, there are hardly any rules as to when to use which preposition. The only way to learn prepositions is by looking them up in a dictionary, reading a lot in English and learning useful phrases off by heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students who are learning English often tell me how difficult it is for them to learn prepositions. They ask questions such as &amp;lsquo;Am I in a restaurant or at a restaurant?&#39;&amp;rsquo;, but I have to tell them that both are OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some circumstances the phrases can have different meanings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you are waiting for someone outside a restaurant, you are at the restaurant, not in the restaurant; but if you are inside, you can be both in or at the restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We commonly use prepositions to show a relationship in space or time or a logical relationship between two or more people, places or things. Prepositions are most commonly followed by a noun phrase or pronoun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I saw him he was waiting for the bus.
I&amp;rsquo;ll meet you in the cafe opposite the station.
It was difficult to sleep during the train journey.
It was the worst storm since the 1990s.
Give that to me.
Two of the guests are vegetarian.
It is of no consequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British English versus American English&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People speaking British English sometimes use different prepositions from people speaking American English too. In the US, they might say: something is different from (the standard) something else, or perhaps that something is different than something else (less acceptable, but still common), but in Britain, you might also hear that: something is different to something else, which sounds very odd to American ears. In US English, they would say Bloomingdales is on 59th Street, but in Britain, they&amp;rsquo;d say Harrods is in Brompton Road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure whether you should write &amp;lsquo;We were in the restaurant,&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;We were at the restaurant,&amp;rsquo; you can search for those phrases using Google Books Ngram Viewer and see that although both are in use, &amp;lsquo;in the restaurant&amp;rsquo; is a bit more common.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Prepositions of place, in, on, at.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/prepositions-of-place-in-on-at/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/prepositions-of-place-in-on-at/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;You sit on a chair.&lt;br&gt;
You sit at a table.&lt;br&gt;
You sleep in a bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You look _ the moon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You ride _ a horse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You live _ a house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You dance _ a party.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At  - A preposition of place which is used to discuss a certain point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In -  A preposition of place which is used to discuss an enclosed space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On -  A preposition of time which is used to discuss a surface.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Regular verbs versus irregular verbs.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/regular-verbs/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/regular-verbs/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;You add -ed to a verb to put it in the past tense; &amp;lsquo;talk&amp;rsquo; becomes &amp;lsquo;talked&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;park&amp;rsquo; becomes &amp;lsquo;parked,&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;offend&amp;rsquo; becomes &amp;lsquo;offended&amp;rsquo;. When you make a verb past tense by adding -ed, it&amp;rsquo;s a regular verb. It&amp;rsquo;s the usual way we make things past tense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English also has verbs that don&amp;rsquo;t follow this pattern: verbs such as &amp;lsquo;am,&amp;rsquo; which becomes &amp;lsquo;was&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;tell,&amp;rsquo; which becomes &amp;lsquo;told&amp;rsquo;; and &amp;lsquo;sing,&amp;rsquo; which becomes &amp;lsquo;sang.&amp;rsquo; These are called irregular verbs because they don&amp;rsquo;t follow the usual pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British English uses irregular verbs more than American English, which is why they say &amp;lsquo;dreamt,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;burnt,&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;learnt&amp;rsquo; in Britain, and &amp;lsquo;dreamed,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;burned,&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;learned&amp;rsquo; in America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are over 370 irregular verbs used in modern English.&lt;br&gt;
The verbs have, go, do, and be are irregular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;have has&lt;br&gt;
go goes&lt;br&gt;
do does&lt;br&gt;
be is&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Seem like, seems like, seems.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/seem-like-seems-like-seem/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/seem-like-seems-like-seem/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Seem means &amp;lsquo;appear in a particular way&amp;rsquo;. We can use it as a linking verb (like be) or with a to-infinitive. We do not normally use seem in the continuous form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seem is a present tense verb which is conjugated like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seem, you seem, we seem, they seem&amp;rsquo;&lt;br&gt;
he seems, she seems, it seems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the only difference between &amp;lsquo;seem&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;seems&amp;rsquo; is in what noun it follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seem as a linking verb is followed by an adjective or, less commonly, a noun:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seem + like is just one possible combination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They seem like very nice people.&lt;br&gt;
You seem like a happy character.&lt;br&gt;
He seems like an intelligent man.&lt;br&gt;
It seems like a friendly animal.&lt;br&gt;
The plan seems like a good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;seem&amp;rsquo; without &amp;lsquo;like&amp;rsquo; is common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems we stood and talked like this, before. We looked at each other in the same way then, but I can&amp;rsquo;t remember where or when.&lt;br&gt;
The trains seem to be running on time.&lt;br&gt;
It seems as if they are all enjoying themselves.&lt;br&gt;
It seems noisy in here tonight.&lt;br&gt;
You seem confident that you will pass the exam.&lt;br&gt;
He seems happy right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seem is a verb that governs infinitive complements and allows Negative-Raising. That means that negation in the infinitive complement of seem, or want, or other Neg-Raising verbs, without a change in meaning. This is not true of most predicates, which don&amp;rsquo;t allow Neg-Raising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of seem to is usually a hedge, or a softener. because they have no reasonable expectation that they should be able to do something. &amp;lsquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to&amp;rsquo; expresses the idea of repeatedly trying without success. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to flatly admit that you can&amp;rsquo;t as long as you keep trying, but you&amp;rsquo;re closer to failure so it seems you can&amp;rsquo;t, while you still hope to succeed. It&amp;rsquo;s often used as a commentary on ongoing attempts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just can&amp;rsquo;t seem to get this jar open!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;It seems that I can&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo; expresses a bit more finality. It&amp;rsquo;s as if you&amp;rsquo;ve seen all the attempts, and while you may succeed in some future attempt, you have say at this point that it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Spacings</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/spacings-improve-readability-text/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/spacings-improve-readability-text/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Spacings improve the readability of your text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect:&lt;br&gt;
If you love something ,then set it free . If it comes back to you , it&amp;rsquo;s yours .&lt;br&gt;
Correct:&lt;br&gt;
If you love something, then set it free. If it comes back to you, it&amp;rsquo;s yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insert one space between each word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insert one space following (not before) periods, commas, semicolons, colons, exclamation points, question marks, and quotation marks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Swallowing your pride.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/swallowing-your-pride/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/swallowing-your-pride/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;When you swallow your pride, you control the urge to be arrogant or proud (which is what you really want to be) and instead you behave in a humble way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had to swallow your pride?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is me swallowing my pride, standing in front of you saying I&amp;rsquo;m sorry for that night.&lt;br&gt;
Taylor Swift&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Syntax</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/syntax/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/syntax/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Syntax is &amp;lsquo;the order of words in which they convey meaning collectively by their connection and relation.&amp;rsquo; Or, more simply put, word order in a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subject, verb, object&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard syntax looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You (S) have broken (V) [my heart. (O)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inversion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inversion is the technique of placing the usual elements of a sentence (subject, verb, object) in reverse, or partially reverse, order. The result is a shift in emphasis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[My heart (O)] you (S) have broken (V).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive voice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive voice is a little like inversion. The object of the sentence (the receiver of the action), which usually ends a sentence, begins it instead. The subject (the doer of the action) falls to the end or disappears entirely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[My heart (receiver)] has been broken by you (doer). OR
[My heart (receiver)] has been broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive voice is more an inversion of meaning than an inversion of syntax. That’s because the grammatical subject of the sentence (heart) is still at the beginning of the sentence and is still followed by the verb. In other words, standard subject + verb order prevails. Yet the emphasis and feel of the sentence are different because the receiver of the action is at the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive voice is used when you want to emphasise the receiver of the action rather than the doer, or when the doer is unknown or unspecified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fire at the school was started sometime between midnight and 4:00 AM.
Money will be raised to repair the damaged classrooms and replace the grammar texts that were apparently used as fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separation of subject and verb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subject and its verb are usually inseparable, but putting a little distance between them now and again adds spark to their connection. Inserting details between the subject and its verb, as a kind of interruption, emphasises the subject and builds anticipation as the reader awaits the verb:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You (S), [love of my life, moon in my heaven,] have broken (V) my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Tenali Rama and the Brinjal Curry</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/curry/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/curry/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A fable is a short story that teaches a lesson or conveys a moral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the moral of this story?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave your answer as a comment on the Home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sri Krishna Devaraya was the emperor of Vizayanagra. He had eight advisors. Tenali Rama was one among them. He was very clever and spontaneous. Sri Krishna Devaraya had some special kind of brinjal plants in his garden. The brinjal was a rare kind, and curry made out of it was very tasty which was loved by the emperor. As it was a rare kind, the garden was guarded and no one was allowed to view the plants without the emperor’s permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, the emperor had arranged dinner for his advisors and the brinjal curry was served. Tenali Rama had enjoyed the brinjal curry very much and went home. But he was unable to forget the taste. He told his wife about the taste of the curry. Tenali Rama’s wife also liked brinjal curry, she asked Tenali Rama to bring home a few brinjals so that she can prepare a curry.  But Tenali Rama knew that the emperor was taking extreme care about the Brinjal plants and he could easily detect any that were missing from his garden. And, the emperor would punish such a thief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Tenali’s wife pleaded with him to take a brinjal from the garden without telling anybody. Tenali Rama had no choice other than stealing a brinjal from the emperor’s garden. One night he went to the garden, jumped the wall and plucked a few brinjals from the garden. By the grace of God, no one had seen him. His wife cooked the brinjals and the curry was very tasty. Like all the mothers, she too loved her son very much and wanted to serve a brinjal curry for him. But Tenali Rama asked her not to do such a thing because if their son reveals to anybody that he had a rare brinjal curry, then they may get caught and punished for stealing a brinjal from the garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But his wife did not agree. She wanted to serve the curry to her son. She was unable to eat the curry alone without serving her child who was sleeping, after doing his homework on the roof of their house. She asked Tenali Rama to find a way so that their son can also taste the brinjal curry.  Tenali Rama also loved his son, so he thought of an idea and with a lot of hesitation went on to the roof to wake up his child with a bucket of water and poured the water on the child. When the child woke up he said “It is raining,  let’s go inside the house and have dinner”.  After going inside the room Tenali changed the clothes of his son and gave him the rice and brinjal curry for his dinner. Tenali Rama told his wife loudly that “it was raining outside, and let the boy sleep in the room”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, the emperor came to know that a few brinjals were missing from his garden.The gardener, who kept a count of each vegetable and flower found that three brinjals were missing. It became a challenging issue for the emperor who took it very seriously. He declared a reward for the person who can catch the thief. Chief advisor Appaji suspected that only Tenali Rama was capable of doing such a thing, and they told the emperor about it. The emperor sent his courtiers and asked Tenali Rama to come immediately. Once Tenali Rama came he asked him about the missing brinjals. Tenali Rama replied, “I was not aware of the missing brinjals”. Then the chief advisor said “Tenali Rama is lying, let’s ask his son”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The king sent his courtiers to bring Tenali Rama’s son. Once his son came, He was asked what vegetable he had in his dinner last night. The child replied: “The brinjal curry and it was very tasty”. Then the advisor told Tenali Rama that he needs to accept his crime. But Tenali Rama said his son had slept very early and he might be saying something which he imagined in his dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the emperor asked the child “can you please explain clearly what you did yesterday after coming from the school?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenali Rama’s son replied that “yesterday after coming from school, I played for a while, and after that I went on to the roof, did my homework, and slept on the roof. But when the rain started, my father came and woke me up.  By that time my clothes were saturated. So we went inside, had dinner and I slept again”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chief advisor Appaji was shocked because there was no rain at all yesterday, and the atmosphere was totally dry. So they thought the child had a dream and freed Tenali Rama without any punishment. However, later Tenali Raman told the truth to the emperor and was pardoned by the emperor for his clever witty idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Than me or than I?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/than-me-or-than-i/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/than-me-or-than-i/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Than is both a subordinating conjunction, as in &amp;lsquo;She is smarter than I am.&amp;rsquo;, and a preposition, as in &amp;lsquo;She is smarter than me&amp;rsquo;. As subject of the clause introduced by the conjunction than, the pronoun must be nominative, and as object of the preposition than, the following pronoun must be in the objective case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two simple rules you can follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is smarter than I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In written English, especially in a formal document such as a business letter or a school assignment, most native speakers believe that the subject pronouns I, he, she, we, and they are correct after than. Therefore, if you want to sound educated and correct, it is safer to use &amp;lsquo;She is smarter than I.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is smarter than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In everyday conversation, however, or in text messages and informal emails, most native speakers use the object pronouns me, him, her, us, and them (even if they tell you that they don&amp;rsquo;t), and if you say &amp;lsquo;She is smarter than I.&amp;rsquo;, many people will think that it sounds unnatural and awkward and possibly even pretentious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in conversation, I recommend that you stick with &amp;lsquo;She is smarter than me.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The 100 best novels.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/100-best-novels/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/100-best-novels/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of the 100 best novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Quixote Miguel De Cervantes&lt;br&gt;
The story of the gentle knight and his servant Sancho Panza has entranced readers for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pilgrim&amp;rsquo;s Progress John Bunyan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one with the Slough of Despond and Vanity Fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinson Crusoe Daniel Defoe&lt;br&gt;
The first English novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gulliver&amp;rsquo;s Travels Jonathan Swift&lt;br&gt;
A wonderful satire that still works for all ages, despite the savagery of Swift’s vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Jones Henry Fielding&lt;br&gt;
The adventures of a high-spirited orphan boy: an unbeatable plot and a lot of sex ending in a blissful marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarissa Samuel Richardson&lt;br&gt;
One of the longest novels in the English language, but unputdownable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tristram Shandy Laurence Sterne&lt;br&gt;
One of the first bestsellers, dismissed by Dr Johnson as too fashionable for its own good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dangerous Liaisons Pierre Choderlos De Laclos&lt;br&gt;
An epistolary novel and a handbook for seducers: foppish, French, and ferocious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emma Jane Austen&lt;br&gt;
Near impossible choice between this and Pride and Prejudice. But Emma never fails to fascinate and annoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankenstein Mary Shelley&lt;br&gt;
Inspired by spending too much time with Shelley and Byron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nightmare Abbey Thomas Love Peacock&lt;br&gt;
A classic miniature: a brilliant satire on the Romantic novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Black Sheep Honore De Balzac&lt;br&gt;
Two rivals fight for the love of a femme fatale. Wrongly overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Charterhouse of Parma Stendhal&lt;br&gt;
Penetrating and compelling chronicle of life in an Italian court in post-Napoleonic France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Count of Monte Christo Alexandre Dumas&lt;br&gt;
A revenge thriller also set in France after Bonaparte: a masterpiece of adventure writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sybil Benjamin Disraeli&lt;br&gt;
Apart from Churchill, no other British political figure shows literary genius.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Copperfield Charles Dickens&lt;br&gt;
This highly autobiographical novel is the one its author liked best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wuthering Heights Emily Bronte&lt;br&gt;
Catherine Earnshaw and Heathcliff have passed into the language. Impossible to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jane Eyre Charlotte Bronte&lt;br&gt;
Obsessive emotional grip and haunting narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanity Fair William Makepeace Thackeray&lt;br&gt;
The improving tale of Becky Sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scarlet Letter Nathaniel Hawthorne&lt;br&gt;
A classic investigation of the American mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moby-Dick Herman Melville&lt;br&gt;
‘Call me Ishmael’ is one of the most famous opening sentences of any novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Madame Bovary Gustave Flaubert&lt;br&gt;
You could summarise this as a story of adultery in provincial France, and miss the point entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Woman in White Wilkie Collins&lt;br&gt;
Gripping mystery novel of concealed identity, abduction, fraud and mental cruelty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice’s Adventures In Wonderland Lewis Carroll&lt;br&gt;
A story written for the nine-year-old daughter of an Oxford don that still baffles most kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little Women Louisa M. Alcott&lt;br&gt;
Victorian bestseller about a New England family of girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Way We Live Now Anthony Trollope&lt;br&gt;
A majestic assault on the corruption of late Victorian England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Karenina Leo Tolstoy&lt;br&gt;
The supreme novel of the married woman’s passion for a younger man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Deronda George Eliot&lt;br&gt;
A passion and an exotic grandeur that is strange and unsettling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brothers Karamazov Fyodor Dostoevsky&lt;br&gt;
Mystical tragedy by the author of Crime and Punishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Portrait of a Lady Henry James&lt;br&gt;
The story of Isabel Archer shows James at his witty and polished best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huckleberry Finn Mark Twain&lt;br&gt;
Twain was a humorist, but this picture of Mississippi life is profoundly moral and still incredibly influential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde Robert Louis Stevenson&lt;br&gt;
A brilliantly suggestive, resonant study of human duality by a natural storyteller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three Men in a Boat Jerome K. Jerome&lt;br&gt;
One of the funniest English books ever written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Picture of Dorian Gray Oscar Wilde&lt;br&gt;
A coded and epigrammatic melodrama inspired by his own tortured homosexuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Diary of a Nobody George Grossmith&lt;br&gt;
This classic of Victorian suburbia will always be renowned for the character of Mr Pooter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jude the Obscure Thomas Hardy&lt;br&gt;
Its savage bleakness makes it one of the first twentieth-century novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Riddle of the Sands Erskine Childers&lt;br&gt;
A prewar invasion-scare spy thriller by a writer later shot for his part in the Irish republican rising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Call of the Wild Jack London&lt;br&gt;
The story of a dog who joins a pack of wolves after his master’s death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nostromo Joseph Conrad&lt;br&gt;
Conrad’s masterpiece: a tale of money, love and revolutionary politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wind in the Willows Kenneth Grahame&lt;br&gt;
This children’s classic was inspired by bedtime stories for Grahame’s son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Search of Lost Time Marcel Proust&lt;br&gt;
An unforgettable portrait of Paris in the belle epoque. Probably the longest novel on this list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rainbow D. H. Lawrence&lt;br&gt;
Novels seized by the police, like this one, have a special afterlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good Soldier Ford Madox Ford&lt;br&gt;
This account of the adulterous lives of two Edwardian couples is a classic of unreliable narration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Thirty-Nine Steps John Buchan&lt;br&gt;
A classic adventure story for boys, jammed with action, violence and suspense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulysses James Joyce&lt;br&gt;
Also pursued by the British police, this is a novel more discussed than read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mrs Dalloway Virginia Woolf&lt;br&gt;
Secures Woolf’s position as one of the great twentieth-century English novelists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Passage to India E. M. Forster&lt;br&gt;
The great novel of the British Raj, it remains a brilliant study of empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Great Gatsby F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;br&gt;
The quintessential Jazz Age novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trial Franz Kafka&lt;br&gt;
The enigmatic story of Joseph K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men Without Women Ernest Hemingway&lt;br&gt;
He is remembered for his novels, but it was the short stories that first attracted notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journey to the End of the Night Louis-Ferdinand Celine&lt;br&gt;
The experiences of an unattractive slum doctor during the Great War: a masterpiece of linguistic innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I Lay Dying William Faulkner&lt;br&gt;
A strange black comedy by an American master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave New World Aldous Huxley&lt;br&gt;
Dystopian fantasy about the world of the seventh century AF (after Ford).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scoop Evelyn Waugh&lt;br&gt;
The supreme Fleet Street novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USA John Dos Passos&lt;br&gt;
An extraordinary trilogy that uses a variety of narrative devices to express the story of America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Sleep Raymond Chandler&lt;br&gt;
Introducing Philip Marlowe: cool, sharp, handsome – and bitterly alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pursuit Of Love Nancy Mitford&lt;br&gt;
An exquisite comedy of manners with countless fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Plague Albert Camus&lt;br&gt;
A mysterious plague sweeps through the Algerian town of Oran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nineteen Eighty-Four George Orwell&lt;br&gt;
This tale of one man’s struggle against totalitarianism has been appropriated the world over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malone Dies Samuel Beckett&lt;br&gt;
Part of a trilogy of astonishing monologues in the black comic voice of the author of Waiting for Godot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catcher in the Rye J.D. Salinger&lt;br&gt;
A week in the life of Holden Caulfield. A cult novel that still mesmerises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wise Blood Flannery O’Connor&lt;br&gt;
A disturbing novel of religious extremism set in the Deep South.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlotte’s Web E. B. White&lt;br&gt;
How Wilbur the pig was saved by the literary genius of a friendly spider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord Of The Rings J. R. R. Tolkien&lt;br&gt;
Enough said!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucky Jim Kingsley Amis&lt;br&gt;
An astonishing debut: the painfully funny English novel of the Fifties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord of the Flies William Golding&lt;br&gt;
Schoolboys become savages: a bleak vision of human nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quiet American Graham Greene&lt;br&gt;
Prophetic novel set in 1950s Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Road Jack Kerouac&lt;br&gt;
The Beat Generation bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lolita Vladimir Nabokov&lt;br&gt;
Humbert Humber&amp;rsquo;s obsession with Lolita is a tour de force of style and narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tin Drum Gunter Grass&lt;br&gt;
Hugely influential, Rabelaisian novel of Hitler&amp;rsquo;s Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things Fall Apart Chinua Achebe&lt;br&gt;
Nigeria at the beginning of colonialism. A classic of African literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie Muriel Spark&lt;br&gt;
A writer who made her debut in The Observer; and her prose is like cut glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Kill A Mockingbird Harper Lee&lt;br&gt;
Scout, a six-year-old girl, narrates an enthralling story of racial prejudice in the Deep South.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catch-22 Joseph Heller&lt;br&gt;
He would be crazy to fly more missions and sane if he didn&amp;rsquo;t, but if he was sane he had to fly them. If he flew them he was crazy and didn’t have to; if he didn’t want to he was sane and had to.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herzog Saul Bellow&lt;br&gt;
Adultery and nervous breakdown in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Hundred Years of Solitude Gabriel Garcia Marquez&lt;br&gt;
A postmodern masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mrs Palfrey at the Claremont Elizabeth Taylor&lt;br&gt;
A haunting, understated study of old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy John Le Carre&lt;br&gt;
A thrilling elegy for post-imperial Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Song of Solomon Toni Morrison&lt;br&gt;
The definitive novelist of the African-American experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bottle Factory Outing Beryl Bainbridge&lt;br&gt;
Macabre comedy of provincial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Executioner’s Song Norman Mailer&lt;br&gt;
This quasi-documentary account of the life and death of Gary Gilmore is possibly his masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If on a Winter’s Night a Traveller Italo Calvino&lt;br&gt;
A strange, compelling story about the pleasures of reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Bend in the River V. S. Naipaul&lt;br&gt;
The finest living writer of English prose. This is his masterpiece: edgily reminiscent of Heart of Darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting for the Barbarians J.M. Coetzee&lt;br&gt;
Bleak but haunting allegory of apartheid by the Nobel prizewinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Housekeeping Marilynne Robinson&lt;br&gt;
Haunting, poetic story, drowned in water and light, about three generations of women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lanark Alasdair Gray&lt;br&gt;
Seething vision of Glasgow. A Scottish classic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York Trilogy Paul Auster&lt;br&gt;
Dazzling metaphysical thriller set in the Manhattan of the 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BFG Roald Dahl&lt;br&gt;
A bestseller by the most popular postwar writer for children of all ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Periodic Table Primo Levi&lt;br&gt;
A prose poem about the delights of chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money Martin Amis&lt;br&gt;
The novel that bags Amis&amp;rsquo;s place on any list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Artist of the Floating World Kazuo Ishiguro&lt;br&gt;
A collaborator from prewar Japan reluctantly discloses his betrayal of friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oscar And Lucinda Peter Carey&lt;br&gt;
A great contemporary love story set in nineteenth-century Australia by double Booker prizewinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Book of Laughter and Forgetting Milan Kundera&lt;br&gt;
Inspired by the Soviet invasion of Czechoslovakia in 1968, this is a magical fusion of history, autobiography and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haroun and the Sea of Stories Salman Rushdie&lt;br&gt;
In this entrancing story Rushdie plays with the idea of narrative itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Confidential James Ellroy&lt;br&gt;
Three LAPD detectives are brought face to face with the secrets of their corrupt and violent careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wise Children Angela Carter&lt;br&gt;
A theatrical extravaganza by a brilliant exponent of magic realism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atonement Ian McEwan&lt;br&gt;
Acclaimed short-story writer achieves a contemporary classic of mesmerising narrative conviction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Lights Philip Pullman&lt;br&gt;
Lyra’s quest weaves fantasy, horror and the play of ideas into a truly great contemporary children’s book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Pastoral Philip Roth&lt;br&gt;
For years, Roth was famous for Portnoy’s Complaint . Recently, he has enjoyed an extraordinary revival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austerlitz W. G. Sebald&lt;br&gt;
Posthumously published volume in a sequence of dream-like fictions spun from memory, photographs and the German past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Acknowledgements: The Guardian; Robert McCrum
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The active and passive voice.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/active-passive-voice/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/active-passive-voice/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The term voice, as a linguistic category, indicates the relationship between the subject of a sentence and its verb. In English, there are two voices — active and passive. If the subject of a sentence performs the action of the verb, the verb is said to in the active voice; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped.&lt;br&gt;
I bathed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The active voice is considered the normal and preferred relationship in English sentences. On the other hand, if the subject is acted upon by the verb, the verb is said to be in the passive voice. There are two ways of casting a verb in the passive voice in English so as to cause the subject to be acted upon by its verb. The foremost way is by using a form of the verb to be with the past participle of a verb, such as in the following examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was stopped. (someone stopped me.)&lt;br&gt;
I was bathed. (someone bathed me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the more common way of the two. It appears in all levels of English and its only restriction is that the verb must be transitive. The second and less common way, is by using a form of the verb to get with the past participle of a verb:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got stopped. (someone stopped me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This second variant is often called the get-passive. It is used in less formal situations, and its use is restricted to a small number of verbs; for example, get killed, get stuck, get hurt, get burned, get shot, get arrested, get paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Structure of the Passive Voice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As previously stated, the passive voice in English is formed by combining a form of the verb to be with the past participle of a transitive verb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active Voice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to stop&lt;br&gt;
I stop&lt;br&gt;
I stopped&lt;br&gt;
I will stop&lt;br&gt;
I would stop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to have stopped&lt;br&gt;
I have stopped&lt;br&gt;
I had stopped&lt;br&gt;
I will have stopped&lt;br&gt;
I would have stopped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive Voice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to be stopped&lt;br&gt;
I am stopped&lt;br&gt;
I was stopped&lt;br&gt;
I will be stopped&lt;br&gt;
I would be stopped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to have been stopped&lt;br&gt;
I have been stopped&lt;br&gt;
I had been stopped&lt;br&gt;
I will have been stopped&lt;br&gt;
I would have been stopped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theoretically, passive voice constructions can appear in any form, but in actual practice with progressive forms, they seem to be confined mostly to the present and past tenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progressive Forms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active Voice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am stopping&lt;br&gt;
I was stopping&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive Voice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am being stopped&lt;br&gt;
I was being stopped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive voice constructions are also used with modal auxiliary verbs, such as in the following examples&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modal Verbs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;can&lt;br&gt;
could&lt;br&gt;
may&lt;br&gt;
might&lt;br&gt;
must&lt;br&gt;
should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active Voice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can stop&lt;br&gt;
I could stop&lt;br&gt;
I may stop&lt;br&gt;
I might stop&lt;br&gt;
I must stop&lt;br&gt;
I should stop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive Voice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can be stopped&lt;br&gt;
I could be stopped&lt;br&gt;
I may be stopped&lt;br&gt;
I might be stopped&lt;br&gt;
I must be stopped&lt;br&gt;
I should be stopped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that the passive-voice construction always appears after the modal auxiliary verbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use of the Passive Voice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more common voice construction in English is the active voice; however, there are three times when the passive voice is the structure of choice for speakers and writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The passive voice allows speakers and writers to keep discourse topics in the subject position over successive clauses while adding new information in the remainder of the clause. Note these two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had just finished paying off my new car when it was towed by the police. Then, on the way to the towing compound, it was rammed by a truck and demolished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first electronic computer was built in England during World War II. It was called the the Colossus, and it was used to decipher Adolf Hitler’s confidential messages to his generals. After the war, it was destroyed so that the world would not learn how the British broke codes. Presently, it is being reconstructed at Bletchley Park in England where it can be viewed by visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The passive voice allows speakers and writers not to mention an agent, especially when information about the agent is unknown, unimportant, obvious, confidential, or difficult to identify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My car was stolen.&lt;br&gt;
A decision has been made.&lt;br&gt;
Much tobacco is grown in Eastern Europe.&lt;br&gt;
A new president has been elected.&lt;br&gt;
Both French and English are spoken in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Passive voice allows speakers and writers to place emphasis on receivers of an action by placing them at the beginning of a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirteen people were injured by a tornado in Florida.&lt;br&gt;
I was robbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agents in a Passive Voice Construction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of passive sentences in English do not include explicit agents to indicate exactly who performed the actions, however agents exist; and they can be indicated, if need be, by a prepositional phrase beginning with by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My car was stolen by someone.&lt;br&gt;
A decision has been made by the group.&lt;br&gt;
Much tobacco is grown in Eastern Europe by farmers.&lt;br&gt;
A new president has been elected by the voters.&lt;br&gt;
Both French and English are spoken in Canada by the populace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These sentences can virtually always be recast in the active voice with the agent moved to the subject position and with no essential change of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone stole my car.&lt;br&gt;
The group has made a decision.&lt;br&gt;
Farmers grow much tobacco in Eastern Europe.&lt;br&gt;
The voters have elected a new president.&lt;br&gt;
The populace speaks both French and English in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although most passive voice sentences in English do not include agents, there are three narrow instances when speakers and writers tend to express them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agent is expressed when it is a proper name indicating an artist, an inventor, a discoverer, or an innovator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mona Lisa was painted by Leonardo da Vinci.&lt;br&gt;
The first electronic computer was built by Tomas Flowers.&lt;br&gt;
The American continent was discovered by Christopher Columbus.&lt;br&gt;
Rubber was first vulcanised by Charles Goodyear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agent is expressed when it is an indefinite noun conveying new information that the speaker or writer thinks is important enough to mention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These works of art were all produced by women.&lt;br&gt;
The corner store was robbed by a masked gunman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agent is expressed when it is an unexpected inanimate noun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirteen people were injured by a tornado in Florida.&lt;br&gt;
All the lights in this building are controlled by computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary of Passive Voice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, passive-voice constructions exhibit the following properties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They contain a form of the verb to be (or to get) plus a past participle of a transitive verb.&lt;br&gt;
They express an action carried out on the subject of the sentence.&lt;br&gt;
They contain an agent, either expressed or more frequently unexpressed.&lt;br&gt;
They can almost always be rewritten in the active voice with the agent moved to the subject position with no essential change of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stative Passive Constructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There exists in English an adjectival construction that resembles the passive voice superficially and is different in meaning. It is a construction using the verb to be with an adjective that is identical in form to a past participle. See these examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank was closed all day yesterday. (It was not open.)&lt;br&gt;
I was married for ten years. (I was not single.)&lt;br&gt;
When I entered the room, I noticed that the chair was broken (It was not intact)&lt;br&gt;
My PC was connected to the internet all last year, and it never incurred a single virus. (It had a connection; it was not disconnected)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although these constructions look identical to a passive voice construction, they do not express an action carried out on the subject of the sentence, they do not contain an explicit or implied agent, and they cannot be rewritten in the active voice. They merely describe the state or condition of the subject of the sentence. And because they describe the state or condition of the subject of the sentence while resembling passive constructions superficially, some linguists call these constructions stative passives. Most stative passives have true passive counterparts as well, as in the four examples below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank was closed at exactly 3 o’clock. (somebody closed it.)&lt;br&gt;
This sentence clearly describes an action and can include a by-phrase, such as in “The bank was closed at exactly 3 o’clock by a security guard.” Its active counterpart would be, “A security guard closed the bank at exactly 3 o’clock.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was married in that chapel. (I had a wedding ceremony.)&lt;br&gt;
This sentence also describes an action and can accept a by-phrase: “I was married in that chapel by a justice of the peace.” Its active counterpart would be “A justice of the peace married me in that chapel last year.” This is a true passive voice construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chair was broken by the weight of the sumo wrestler, when he sat down.&lt;br&gt;
The active counterpart would be, “The weight of the sumo wrestler broke the chair when he sat down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PC was connected to the internet just a few minutes ago, and it already has a virus. (received a connection; became connected)&lt;br&gt;
The active variant would be “Somebody connected my PC to the internet. . .”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the context is the determining factor as to whether an action or a state is being described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A salient type of stative passive construction is the combination of the verb to be with adjectives that describe an emotional state. There are about three dozen of them in common use. They are derived from verbs and are identical in form to past participles, most of them ending in ed; but instead of indicating an action, they refer to the experiencing of an emotion.&lt;br&gt;
Note these examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was bored&lt;br&gt;
I was depressed&lt;br&gt;
I was exhausted&lt;br&gt;
I was interested&lt;br&gt;
I was tired&lt;br&gt;
I was relieved&lt;br&gt;
I was satisfied&lt;br&gt;
I was shocked&lt;br&gt;
I was disgusted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I felt bored)&lt;br&gt;
(I felt depressed)&lt;br&gt;
(I felt exhausted)&lt;br&gt;
(I felt interested)&lt;br&gt;
(I felt tired)&lt;br&gt;
(I felt relieved)&lt;br&gt;
(I felt satisfied)&lt;br&gt;
(I felt shocked)&lt;br&gt;
(I felt disgusted)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analogous to an agent by-phrase, these adjectives most often take a range of prepositions to connect them to the cause of the emotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was exhausted from so much work.&lt;br&gt;
I was interested in computers.&lt;br&gt;
I was bored with my classes.&lt;br&gt;
I was tired of hearing so many excuses.&lt;br&gt;
I was relieved at the outcome of the election.&lt;br&gt;
I was depressed over my divorce.&lt;br&gt;
I was satisfied with my progress.&lt;br&gt;
I was shocked at your behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, however, even some of these constructions may have a true passive interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was shocked by your behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In which case it could have an active counterpart of “Your behaviour shocked me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary of True Passive-Voice Constructions, Versus Stative-Passive Constructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important points to remember when you want to compare these two constructions are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In true passive constructions, an action is carried out on the subject of the sentence, there is an agent either expressed or unexpressed, there exists an active voice counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In stative passive constructions, the state or condition of the subject of the sentence is described, there is no agent,&lt;br&gt;
there is no active voice counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all true passive voice constructions have stative passive counterparts, but many, many do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Alchemist</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/alchemist-novel-paulo-coelho/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/alchemist-novel-paulo-coelho/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The Alchemist  is a novel by Brazilian author Paulo Coelho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First published in 1988. Originally written in Portuguese, it became an
international bestseller translated into some 70 languages as of
2016. An allegorical novel that follows a young Andalusian shepherd in
his journey to Egypt, after having a recurring dream of finding treasure
there. Over the years there have been film and theatrical adaptations of
the work and musical interpretations of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The ampersand &amp;</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-ampersand/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-ampersand/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The ampersand &amp;amp; is the logogram &amp;amp;, representing the conjunction &amp;lsquo;and&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You generally shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use the ampersand, except in the most informal situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should only use the ampersand when the rest of the name is also an abbreviation (AT&amp;amp;T) and in common expressions (R&amp;amp;D). There are no spaces on either side of the ampersand when it is used that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an English learner you should avoid using the ampersand altogether. Use &amp;lsquo;and&amp;rsquo; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Apostrophe</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-apostrophe/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-apostrophe/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The apostrophe has three uses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To form possessives of nouns.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
To show the omission of letters.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
To indicate certain plurals of lowercase letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forming Possessives of Nouns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see if you need to make a possessive, turn the phrase around and make it an &amp;ldquo;of the&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; phrase.
For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the boy&amp;rsquo;s hat = the hat of the boy&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
three days&amp;rsquo; journey = journey of three days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the noun after &amp;ldquo;of&amp;rdquo; is a building, an object, or a piece of furniture, then no apostrophe is needed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;room of the hotel = hotel room&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
door of the car = car door&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
leg of the table = table leg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve determined whether you need to make a possessive, follow these rules to create one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &amp;rsquo;s to the singular form of the word (even if it ends in -s):&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
the owner&amp;rsquo;s car&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
James&amp;rsquo;s hat (James&amp;rsquo; hat is also acceptable).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For plural, proper nouns that are possessive, use an apostrophe after the &amp;rsquo;s&amp;rsquo;:
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Eggleses&amp;rsquo; presentation was good.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Eggleses are a husband and wife consultant team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &amp;rsquo;s to the plural forms that do not end in -s:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
the children&amp;rsquo;s game&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
the geese&amp;rsquo;s honking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;add &#39; to the end of plural nouns that end in -s:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
two cats&amp;rsquo; toys&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
three friends&amp;rsquo; letters&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
the countries&amp;rsquo; laws&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;add &amp;rsquo;s to the end of compound words:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
my brother-in-law&amp;rsquo;s money&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;add &amp;rsquo;s to the last noun to show joint possession of an object:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Todd and Anne&amp;rsquo;s apartment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Showing omission of letters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apostrophes are used in contractions. A contraction is a word (or set of numbers) in which one or more letters (or numbers) have been omitted. The apostrophe shows this omission. Contractions are common in speaking and in informal writing. To use an apostrophe to create a contraction, place an apostrophe where the omitted letter(s) would go. Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t = do not&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m = I am&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
he&amp;rsquo;ll = he will&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
who&amp;rsquo;s = who is&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t = should not&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
didn&amp;rsquo;t = did notv
could&amp;rsquo;ve= could have (NOT &amp;ldquo;could of&amp;rdquo;!)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&amp;lsquo;60 = 1960&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forming plurals of lowercase letters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apostrophes are used to form plurals of letters that appear in lowercase; here the rule appears to be more typographical than grammatical, e.g. &amp;ldquo;three ps&amp;rdquo; versus &amp;ldquo;three p&amp;rsquo;s.&amp;rdquo; To form the plural of a lowercase letter, place &amp;rsquo;s after the letter. There is no need for apostrophes indicating a plural on capitalised letters, numbers, and symbols (though keep in mind that some editors, teachers, and professors still prefer them). Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p&amp;rsquo;s and q&amp;rsquo;s = minding your p&amp;rsquo;s and q&amp;rsquo;s is a phrase believed to be taken from the early days of the printing press when letters were set in presses backwards so they would appear on the printed page correctly. Although the origins of this phrase are disputed, the expression was used commonly to mean, &amp;ldquo;Be careful, don&amp;rsquo;t make a mistake.&amp;rdquo; Today, the term also indicates maintaining politeness, possibly from &amp;ldquo;mind your pleases and thank-yous.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nita&amp;rsquo;s mother constantly stressed minding one&amp;rsquo;s p&amp;rsquo;s and q&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
three Macintosh G4s = three of the Macintosh model G4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three G4s currently used in the writing classroom.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;many &amp;amp;s = many ampersands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That printed page has too many &amp;amp;s on it.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
the 1960s = the years in decade from 1960 to 1969&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1960s were a time of great social unrest.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
The &amp;rsquo;60s were a time of great social unrest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t use apostrophes for personal pronouns, the relative pronoun who, or for noun plurals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apostrophes should not be used with possessive pronouns because possessive pronouns already show possession—they don&amp;rsquo;t need an apostrophe. His, her, its, my, yours, ours are all possessive pronouns. However, indefinite pronouns, such as one, anyone, other, no one, and anybody, can be made possessive. Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCORRECT: his&amp;rsquo; book&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
CORRECT: his book&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
CORRECT: one&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
CORRECT: anybody&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCORRECT: Who&amp;rsquo;s dog is this?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
CORRECT: Whose dog is this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCORRECT: The group made it&amp;rsquo;s decision.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
CORRECT: The group made its decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Its and it&amp;rsquo;s are not the same thing. It&amp;rsquo;s is a contraction for &amp;ldquo;it is&amp;rdquo; and its is a possessive pronoun meaning &amp;ldquo;belonging to it.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s raining out = it is raining out. A simple way to remember this rule is the fact that you don&amp;rsquo;t use an apostrophe for the possessive his or hers, so don&amp;rsquo;t do it with its!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCORRECT: a friend of yours&#39;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
CORRECT: a friend of yours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCORRECT: She waited for three hours&amp;rsquo; to get her ticket.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
CORRECT: She waited for three hours to get her ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The articles in English are a, an and the.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/articles-a-an-and-the/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/articles-a-an-and-the/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The learner has to decide noun-by-noun which one of the articles to use. In fact, there are four choices to make, because sometimes no article is necessary. Native-speakers, of course, use the articles correctly without thinking. English learners, on the other hand, need to have some guidelines for making the right choice, particularly those learners whose own language does not have articles, such as Japanese or Korean. The guidelines that follow here should help ESL students to a basic understanding of English article use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important first step in choosing the correct article is to categorise the noun as count or uncount:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A count noun is a noun that can have a number in front of it: 1 teacher, 3 books, 76 trombones, 1,000,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An uncount noun is a noun that cannot have a number put in front of it: 1 water, 2 lucks, 10 airs, 21 oils, 39 informations. Once you have correctly categorized the noun (using your dictionary if necessary), the following rules apply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncount nouns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot say a/an with an uncount noun.&lt;br&gt;
You cannot put a number in front of an uncount noun. (You cannot make an uncount noun plural.)&lt;br&gt;
You use an uncount noun with no article if you mean that thing in general.&lt;br&gt;
You use the with an uncount noun when you are talking about a particular example of that thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count nouns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can put a number in front of a count noun. (You can make a count noun plural.)&lt;br&gt;
You can put both a/an and the in front of a count noun.&lt;br&gt;
You must put an article in front of a singular count noun.&lt;br&gt;
You use a plural count noun with no article if you mean all or any of that thing.&lt;br&gt;
You usually use a/an with a count noun the first time you say or write that noun.&lt;br&gt;
You use the with count nouns:&lt;br&gt;
the second and subsequent times you use the noun in a piece of speech or writing&lt;br&gt;
when the listener knows what you are referring to (maybe because there is only one of that thing)&lt;br&gt;
You use an (not a) when the next word (adverb, adjective, noun) starts with a vowel sound.&lt;br&gt;
Note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above rules apply whether there is or there is not an adjective in front of the noun.&lt;br&gt;
Some nouns can be either count or uncount, depending on the context and meaning:&lt;br&gt;
Do you have paper? I want to draw a picture. (uncount = a sheet of paper)&lt;br&gt;
Can you get me a paper when you’re at the shop? (count = a newspaper)&lt;br&gt;
Uncount nouns are often preceded by phrases such as: a lot of .. (luck), a piece of .. (cake), a bottle of .. (milk), a grain of .. (rice).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of an article, the noun can also be preceded by a determiner such as this, that, some, many or my, his, our, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following are some of the most important guidelines, with example sentences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You use an uncount noun with no article if you mean all or any of that thing.&lt;br&gt;
I need help!&lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t eat cheese.&lt;br&gt;
Do you like music?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You use the with an uncount noun when you are talking about a particular example of that thing.&lt;br&gt;
Thanks for the help you gave me yesterday.&lt;br&gt;
I didn&amp;rsquo;t eat the cheese. It was green!&lt;br&gt;
Did you like the music they played at the dance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You usually use a/an with a count noun the first time you say or write that noun.&lt;br&gt;
Can I borrow a pencil, please?&lt;br&gt;
There&amp;rsquo;s a cat in the garden!&lt;br&gt;
Do you have an mp3 player?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You use the with count nouns the second and subsequent times you use the noun, or when the listener already knows what you are referring to (maybe because there is only one of that thing).&lt;br&gt;
Where&amp;rsquo;s the pencil I lent you yesterday?&lt;br&gt;
I think the cat belongs to the new neighbours.&lt;br&gt;
I dropped the mp3 player and it broke.&lt;br&gt;
Please shut the door!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You use a plural count noun with no article if you mean all or any of that thing.&lt;br&gt;
I on&amp;rsquo;t like dogs.&lt;br&gt;
Do they have children?&lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t need questions. Give me answers!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The above rules apply whether there is or there is not an adjective in front of the noun.&lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t eat German cheese.&lt;br&gt;
Can I borrow a red pencil, please?&lt;br&gt;
There&amp;rsquo;s an extremely large cat in the garden!&lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t like small, noisy children.&lt;br&gt;
This page contains short, generalised information about this enormously complex aspect of English grammar. For more detailed information, consult a good reference work such as Swan&amp;rsquo;s Practical English Usage. And do not worry too much about article mistakes; only very rarely will they cause your listener or reader to misunderstand you!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The articles.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/articles/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/articles/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Sunday _ twentieth of May, _ sunny day here in Sydney. I am going to make _ omelette with ham and avocado for my lunch and _ nice cup of black coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, an, a, a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an, a, the, a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a, an, the, a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, a, an, a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the, a, a, an&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two articles in English are a/an and the.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word a (which becomes an when the next word begins with a vowel (a, e, i, o, u) is called the indefinite article because the noun it goes with is indefinite or general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word the is known as the definite article and indicates a specific thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;lsquo;the&amp;rsquo; is one of the most common words in English. It is our only definite article. Nouns in English are preceded by the definite article when the speaker believes that the listener already knows what he is referring to. The speaker may believe this for many different reasons, some of which are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the to refer to something which has already been mentioned.&lt;br&gt;
Use the when you assume there is just one of something in that place, even if it has not been mentioned before.&lt;br&gt;
Use the in sentences or clauses where you define or identify a particular person or object.&lt;br&gt;
Use the to refer to people or objects that are unique.&lt;br&gt;
Use the before superlatives and ordinal numbers.&lt;br&gt;
Use the with decades.&lt;br&gt;
Use the with clauses introduced by only.
Use the with names of geographical areas, rivers, mountain ranges, groups of islands, canals, and oceans.&lt;br&gt;
Use the with countries that have plural names.&lt;br&gt;
Use the with newspaper names.&lt;br&gt;
Use the with the names of famous buildings, works of art, museums, or monuments.&lt;br&gt;
Use the with the names of hotels and restaurants, unless these are named after a person.&lt;br&gt;
Use the with the names of families, but not with the names of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Auxiliary Verbs.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-auxiliary-verbs/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-auxiliary-verbs/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;An auxiliary verb is used in forming the tenses, moods, and voices of other verbs. The primary auxiliary verbs in English are be, do, and have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The verb to be.&lt;br&gt;
The verb to do.&lt;br&gt;
The verb to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every sentence must have a verb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To depict achievable activities, writers use action verbs.&lt;br&gt;
To describe conditions, writers choose linking verbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be, do, and have are both stand-alone verbs and auxiliary verbs. When these verbs are auxiliary, you will find them teamed with other verbs to complete the verb phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the auxiliary verbs. You can conjugate be, do, and have; the modal auxiliaries, however, never change form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be - am, is, are, was, were, being, been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do - does, do, did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have - has, had, having.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modal auxiliaries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;can, could, may, might, must, ought to, shall, should, will, would.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The difference between you, your, you&#39;ll and you&#39;re.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/you-your-youll-and-youre/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/you-your-youll-and-youre/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;You&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, the pronoun you refers to the person or group of people that the speaker is talking to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your is the possessive form of the pronoun you and is used as a second-person possessive adjective meaning &amp;lsquo;of or relating to you or yourself or yourselves especially as possessor or possessors.&amp;rsquo; Since it is a possessive adjective, it is always followed by a noun or a gerund, which belongs to or are associated with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contraction of you will or you shall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re is a contraction of you are. It has no other uses. If you cannot expand it to you are in your sentence, then it is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a few sentences using you, your, you&amp;rsquo;ll and you&amp;rsquo;re.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll find you in the morning sun and when the night is new, I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at the moon, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be seeing you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see your face in every flower, your eyes in stars above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll never know just how much I miss you, you&amp;rsquo;ll never know just how much I care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re the cream in my coffee, I would be lost without you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will tell him myself, and &amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo;ll&amp;rsquo; listen at the door, and Natasha ran across the drawing room to the dancing hall, where Denisov was sitting on the same chair by the clavichord with his face in his hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the salesperson rings up &amp;lsquo;your&amp;rsquo; purchase, no one tells him he had better forget what shoes he sold you with that suit and not to use that information to advise any future clients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The modal auxiliary would.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/would-modal-auxiliaries/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/would-modal-auxiliaries/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The modal auxiliary would (negative would not, which is often contracted to wouldn&amp;rsquo;t) has several uses. One of them is in making a kind of &amp;lsquo;artificial past&amp;rsquo; for will in indirect (reported) speech. Another is in making polite requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would is also commonly used in the expression would like. This expression (which is often contracted to &amp;rsquo;d like with&lt;br&gt;
pronouns) does not mean &amp;lsquo;like.&amp;rsquo; Instead, it means want&lt;br&gt;
(though it is &amp;lsquo;softer,&amp;rsquo; less direct, and much more polite).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want more coffee. (very direct)&lt;br&gt;
Do you want to come with us? (very direct)&lt;br&gt;
Mr. Jones wants to say something. (very direct)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentences with Would Like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like some more coffee. (less direct, more polite)&lt;br&gt;
Would you like to come with us? (less direct, more polite)&lt;br&gt;
Mr. Jones would like to say something. (less direct, more polite)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When would like is contracted to &amp;rsquo;d like (I&amp;rsquo;d like, you&amp;rsquo;d like, she&amp;rsquo;d like, etc.), the contraction for would is very difficult to hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In very casual speech, the end of would often combines with the beginning of you to make a new sound. As a result, Would you sounds&lt;br&gt;
something like &amp;lsquo;Wouldja&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldja like some coffee? (Would you like some coffee?)&lt;br&gt;
Wouldja like to dance? (Would you like to dance?)&lt;br&gt;
Wouldja like something to eat? ( Would you like something to eat?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldja is a spoken form, not a standard written form. In writing, it is not acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In very casual speech, both would and you are sometimes omitted entirely in questions:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like some coffee? (Would you like some coffee?)&lt;br&gt;
Like to dance? (Would you like to dance?)&lt;br&gt;
Like something to eat? (Would you like something to eat?)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Nightingale and the Rose</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-nightingale/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-nightingale/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;“She said that she would dance with me if I brought her red roses,” cried the young Student; “but in all my garden there is no red rose.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From her nest in the holm-oak tree the Nightingale heard him, and she looked out through the leaves, and wondered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No red rose in all my garden!” he cried, and his beautiful eyes filled with tears. “Ah, on what little things does happiness depend! I have read all that the wise men have written, and all the secrets of philosophy are mine, yet for want of a red rose is my life made wretched.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Here at last is a true lover,” said the Nightingale. “Night after night have I sung of him, though I knew him not: night after night have I told his story to the stars, and now I see him. His hair is dark as the hyacinth-blossom, and his lips are red as the rose of his desire; but passion has made his face like pale ivory, and sorrow has set her seal upon his brow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Prince gives a ball to-morrow night,” murmured the young Student, “and my love will be of the company. If I bring her a red rose she will dance with me till dawn. If I bring her a red rose, I shall hold her in my arms, and she will lean her head upon my shoulder, and her hand will be clasped in mine. But there is no red rose in my garden, so I shall sit lonely, and she will pass me by. She will have no heed of me, and my heart will break.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Here indeed is the true lover,” said the Nightingale. “What I sing of, he suffers—what is joy to me, to him is pain. Surely Love is a wonderful thing. It is more precious than emeralds, and dearer than fine opals. Pearls and pomegranates cannot buy it, nor is it set forth in the marketplace. It may not be purchased of the merchants, nor can it be weighed out in the balance for gold.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The musicians will sit in their gallery,” said the young Student, “and play upon their stringed instruments, and my love will dance to the sound of the harp and the violin. She will dance so lightly that her feet will not touch the floor, and the courtiers in their gay dresses will throng round her. But with me she will not dance, for I have no red rose to give her”; and he flung himself down on the grass, and buried his face in his hands, and wept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why is he weeping?” asked a little Green Lizard, as he ran past him with his tail in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why, indeed?” said a Butterfly, who was fluttering about after a sunbeam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why, indeed?” whispered a Daisy to his neighbour, in a soft, low voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He is weeping for a red rose,” said the Nightingale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For a red rose?” they cried; “how very ridiculous!” and the little Lizard, who was something of a cynic, laughed outright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Nightingale understood the secret of the Student’s sorrow, and she sat silent in the oak-tree, and thought about the mystery of Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly she spread her brown wings for flight, and soared into the air. She passed through the grove like a shadow, and like a shadow she sailed across the garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the centre of the grass-plot was standing a beautiful Rose-tree, and when she saw it she flew over to it, and lit upon a spray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Give me a red rose,” she cried, “and I will sing you my sweetest song.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Tree shook its head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My roses are white,” it answered; “as white as the foam of the sea, and whiter than the snow upon the mountain.
But go to my brother who grows round the old sun-dial, and perhaps he will give you what you want.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Nightingale flew over to the Rose-tree that was growing round the old sun-dial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Give me a red rose,” she cried, “and I will sing you my sweetest song.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Tree shook its head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My roses are yellow,” it answered; “as yellow as the hair of the mermaiden who sits upon an amber throne, and yellower than the daffodil that blooms in the meadow before the mower comes with his scythe. But go to my brother who grows beneath the Student’s window, and perhaps he will give you what you want.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Nightingale flew over to the Rose-tree that was growing beneath the Student’s window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Give me a red rose,” she cried, “and I will sing you my sweetest song.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Tree shook its head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My roses are red,” it answered, “as red as the feet of the dove, and redder than the great fans of coral that wave and wave in the ocean-cavern. But the winter has chilled my veins, and the frost has nipped my buds, and the storm has broken my branches, and I shall have no roses at all this year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One red rose is all I want,” cried the Nightingale, “only one red rose! Is there no way by which I can get it?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There is away,” answered the Tree; “but it is so terrible that I dare not tell it to you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tell it to me,” said the Nightingale, “I am not afraid.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you want a red rose,” said the Tree, “you must build it out of music by moonlight, and stain it with your own heart’s-blood. You must sing to me with your breast against a thorn. All night long you must sing to me, and the thorn must pierce your heart, and your life-blood must flow into my veins, and become mine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Death is a great price to pay for a red rose,” cried the Nightingale, “and Life is very dear to all. It is pleasant to sit in the green wood, and to watch the Sun in his chariot of gold, and the Moon in her chariot of pearl. Sweet is the scent of the hawthorn, and sweet are the bluebells that hide in the valley, and the heather that blows on the hill. Yet Love is better than Life, and what is the heart of a bird compared to the heart of a man?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So she spread her brown wings for flight, and soared into the air. She swept over the garden like a shadow, and like a shadow she sailed through the grove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The young Student was still lying on the grass, where she had left him, and the tears were not yet dry in his beautiful eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be happy,” cried the Nightingale, “be happy; you shall have your red rose. I will build it out of music by moonlight, and stain it with my own heart’s-blood. All that I ask of you in return is that you will be a true lover, for Love is wiser than Philosophy, though she is wise, and mightier than Power, though he is mighty. Flame-coloured are his wings, and coloured like flame is his body. His lips are sweet as honey, and his breath is like frankincense.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student looked up from the grass, and listened, but he could not understand what the Nightingale was saying to him, for he only knew the things that are written down in books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Oak-tree understood, and felt sad, for he was very fond of the little Nightingale who had built her nest in his branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sing me one last song,” he whispered; “I shall feel very lonely when you are gone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Nightingale sang to the Oak-tree, and her voice was like water bubbling from a silver jar.
When she had finished her song the Student got up, and pulled a note-book and a lead-pencil out of his pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She has form,” he said to himself, as he walked away through the grove—“that cannot be denied to her; but has she got feeling? I am afraid not. In fact, she is like most artists; she is all style, without any sincerity. She would not sacrifice herself for others. She thinks merely of music, and everybody knows that the arts are selfish. Still, it must be admitted that she has some beautiful notes in her voice. What a pity it is that they do not mean anything, or do any practical good.” And he went into his room, and lay down on his little pallet-bed, and began to think of his love; and, after a time, he fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when the Moon shone in the heavens the Nightingale flew to the Rose-tree, and set her breast against the thorn. All night long she sang with her breast against the thorn, and the cold crystal Moon leaned down and listened. All night long she sang, and the thorn went deeper and deeper into her breast, and her life-blood ebbed away from her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She sang first of the birth of love in the heart of a boy and a girl. And on the top-most spray of the Rose-tree there blossomed a marvellous rose, petal following petal, as song followed song. Pale was it, at first, as the mist that hangs over the river—pale as the feet of the morning, and silver as the wings of the dawn. As the shadow of a rose in a mirror of silver, as the shadow of a rose in a water-pool, so was the rose that blossomed on the topmost spray of the Tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Tree cried to the Nightingale to press closer against the thorn. “Press closer, little Nightingale,” cried the Tree, “or the Day will come before the rose is finished.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Nightingale pressed closer against the thorn, and louder and louder grew her song, for she sang of the birth of passion in the soul of a man and a maid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a delicate flush of pink came into the leaves of the rose, like the flush in the face of the bridegroom when he kisses the lips of the bride. But the thorn had not yet reached her heart, so the rose’s heart remained white, for only a Nightingale’s heart’s-blood can crimson the heart of a rose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the Tree cried to the Nightingale to press closer against the thorn. “Press closer, little Nightingale,” cried the Tree, “or the Day will come before the rose is finished.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Nightingale pressed closer against the thorn, and the thorn touched her heart, and a fierce pang of pain shot through her. Bitter, bitter was the pain, and wilder and wilder grew her song, for she sang of the Love that is perfected by Death, of the Love that dies not in the tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the marvellous rose became crimson, like the rose of the eastern sky. Crimson was the girdle of petals, and crimson as a ruby was the heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Nightingale’s voice grew fainter, and her little wings began to beat, and a film came over her eyes. Fainter and fainter grew her song, and she felt something choking her in her throat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then she gave one last burst of music. The white Moon heard it, and she forgot the dawn, and lingered on in the sky. The red rose heard it, and it trembled all over with ecstasy, and opened its petals to the cold morning air. Echo bore it to her purple cavern in the hills, and woke the sleeping shepherds from their dreams. It floated through the reeds of the river, and they carried its message to the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Look, look!” cried the Tree, “the rose is finished now”; but the Nightingale made no answer, for she was lying dead in the long grass, with the thorn in her heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at noon the Student opened his window and looked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why, what a wonderful piece of luck!” he cried; “here is a red rose! I have never seen any rose like it in all my life. It is so beautiful that I am sure it has a long Latin name”; and he leaned down and plucked it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he put on his hat, and ran up to the Professor’s house with the rose in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The daughter of the Professor was sitting in the doorway winding blue silk on a reel, and her little dog was lying at her feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You said that you would dance with me if I brought you a red rose,” cried the Student. “Here is the reddest rose in all the world. You will wear it to-night next your heart, and as we dance together it will tell you how I love you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the girl frowned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am afraid it will not go with my dress,” she answered; “and, besides, the Chamberlain’s nephew has sent me some real jewels, and everybody knows that jewels cost far more than flowers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, upon my word, you are very ungrateful,” said the Student angrily; and he threw the rose into the street, where it fell into the gutter, and a cart-wheel went over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ungrateful!” said the girl. “I tell you what, you are very rude; and, after all, who are you? Only a Student. Why, I don’t believe you have even got silver buckles to your shoes as the Chamberlain’s nephew has”; and she got up from her chair and went into the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What a silly thing Love is,” said the Student as he walked away. “It is not half as useful as Logic, for it does not prove anything, and it is always telling one of things that are not going to happen, and making one believe things that are not true. In fact, it is quite unpractical, and, as in this age to be practical is everything, I shall go back to Philosophy and study Metaphysics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he returned to his room and pulled out a great dusty book, and began to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Old Man at the Bridge.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/a-very-short-story/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/a-very-short-story/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;An old man with steel rimmed spectacles and very dusty clothes sat by the side of the road. There was a pontoon bridge across the river and carts, trucks, and men, women and children were crossing it. The mule-drawn carts staggered up the steep bank from the bridge with soldiers helping push against the spokes of the wheels. The trucks ground up and away heading out of it all and the peasants plodded along in the ankle deep dust. But the old man sat there without moving. He was too tired to go any farther.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was my business to cross the bridge, explore the bridgehead beyond and find out to what point the enemy had advanced. I did this and returned over the bridge. There were not so many carts now and very few people on foot, but the old man was still there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where do you come from?&amp;rdquo; I asked him. &amp;ldquo;From San Carlos,&amp;rdquo; he said, and smiled. That was his native town and so it gave him pleasure to mention it and he smiled.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;I was taking care of animals,&amp;rdquo; he explained. &amp;ldquo;Oh,&amp;rdquo; I said, not quite understanding. &amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;I stayed, you see, taking care of animals. I was the last one to leave the town of San Carlos.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He did not look like a shepherd nor a herdsman and I looked at his black dusty clothes and his gray dusty face and his steel rimmed spectacles and said, &amp;ldquo;What animals were they?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Various animals,&amp;rdquo; he said, and shook his head. &amp;ldquo;I had to leave them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
I was watching the bridge and the African looking country of the Ebro Delta and wondering how long now it would be before we would see the enemy, and listening all the while for the first noises that would signal that ever mysterious event called contact, and the old man still sat there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What animals were they?&amp;rdquo; I asked.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;There were three animals altogether,&amp;rdquo; he explained. &amp;ldquo;There were two goats and a cat and then there were four pairs of pigeons.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
And you had to leave them?&amp;rdquo; I asked.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Yes. Because of the artillery. The captain told me to go because of the artillery.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;And you have no family?&amp;rdquo; I asked, watching the far end of the bridge where a few last carts were hurrying down the slope of the bank.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;only the animals I stated. The cat, of course, will be all right. A cat can look out for itself, but I cannot think what will become of the others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What politics have you?&amp;rdquo; I asked.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;I am without politics,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;I am seventy-six years old. I have come twelve kilometers now and I think now I can go no further.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;This is not a good place to stop,&amp;rdquo; I said. &amp;ldquo;If you can make it, there are trucks up the road where it forks for Tortosa.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;I will wait a while,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;quot; and then I will go. Where do the trucks go?&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Towards Barcelona,&amp;rdquo; I told him.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;I know no one in that direction,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;but thank you very much. Thank you again very much.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked at me very blankly and tiredly, and then said, having to share his worry with someone, &amp;ldquo;The cat will be all right, I am sure. There is no need to be unquiet about the cat. But the others. Now what do you think about the others?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Why they&amp;rsquo;ll probably come through it all right.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;You think so?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Why not,&amp;rdquo; I said, watching the far bank where now there were no carts.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;But what will they do under the artillery when I was told to leave because of the artillery?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Did you leave the dove cage unlocked?&amp;rdquo; I asked. &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Then they&amp;rsquo;ll fly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Yes, certainly they&amp;rsquo;ll fly. But the others. It&amp;rsquo;s better not to think about the others,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;If you are rested I would go,&amp;rdquo; I urged. &amp;ldquo;Get up and try to walk now.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Thank you,&amp;rdquo; he said and got to his feet, swayed from side to side and then sat down backwards in the dust.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;I was taking care of animals,&amp;rdquo; he said dully, but no longer to me. &amp;ldquo;I was only taking care of animals.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was nothing to do about him. It was Easter Sunday and the Fascists were advancing toward the Ebro. It was a grey overcast day with a low ceiling so their planes were not up. That and the fact that cats know how to look after themselves was all the good luck that old man would ever have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The order of words in a sentence.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/word-order-syntax/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/word-order-syntax/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The order of words in a sentence is very important. A change in word order often results in a change of meaning. Many other languages use inflection, a change in the form of words, to show how the parts of a sentence function. English has very few inflections, so the place that a word occupies in a sentence, its syntax, is the most important feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sydney. first in Today a cool here is Friday the rainy day of, and February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rearrange the words, using all of the words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Pied Piper legend.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/pied-piper-hamelin/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/pied-piper-hamelin/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The Pied Piper legend originated in Hamelin, Germany during the middle ages. As the story goes, the town was
struggling with a rat infestation problem and was desperate for relief.
A mysterious man in “pied clothing” approached the mayor and promised he
could rid the city of its problem in return for payment of 1000
guilders. They mayor agreed, and the man played a magical pipe to lure
all the city’s rats to a nearby body of water, where they drowned. When
the Piper returned for his reward, the mayor refused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>The Verb to Do</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-verb-to-do/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/the-verb-to-do/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The verb to do can be used as an auxiliary and a main verb. It is often used in questions.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I / you / we / they&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Present:  do&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Past:  did&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Perfect: have / had done&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Continuous: am / are / were doing&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
he / she / it&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Present: does&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Past: did&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Perfect: has / had done&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Continuous: is / was doing&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
In Present Simple third person (he, she, it), add an &amp;lsquo;es&amp;rsquo; to a verb that ends in ‘o’:
do &amp;gt; does / go&amp;gt; goes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an action verb:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
John always does his homework on time.
Street sweepers do a lot of work around the city.
Paul did a great job on his science report for school.
You have done nothing all day!
I am doing the best I can!
Your customer doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand the contract.
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about me.
Your friends didn&amp;rsquo;t get the email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Do you want to go to the concert?
Does your cat live outside or in the house?
Does your sister always talk so much on the phone?
Did you catch the train this morning?
Don&amp;rsquo;t you ever visit your relatives?
Didn&amp;rsquo;t Mr. Jones call you?
Where do you want to send the letter?
Why does she always shout like that?
How much do these apples cost?
Why don&amp;rsquo;t you ever tidy up your room?
When did they arrive at school?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>There was or there were.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/there-was-or-there-were/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/there-was-or-there-were/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;It depends on the subject and whether it is singular or plural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As at 8.30AM Thursday, the nineteenth of April, there were 323 members in this group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a sentence or phrase begins with there, the subject comes after the verb. In this phrase, that subject is members, which is plural. Therefore, the verb should be were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As at 8.30AM Thursday, the nineteenth of April, there was only one admin in this group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this phrase, that subject is admin, which is singular. Therefore, the verb should be was.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Thomas Edison</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/edison/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/edison/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the moral of this story?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Edison tried two thousand different materials in search of a filament for the light bulb. When none worked satisfactorily, his assistant complained, “All our work is in vain. We have learned nothing, not sure if we can use electricity properly.” Edison replied very confidently, “Oh, we have come a long way and we have learned a lot. We know that there are two thousand elements which we cannot use to make a good light bulb.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Too, to and two.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/to-too-and-two/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/to-too-and-two/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;There is often confusion over the words too and to. Both words have two uses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too means as well or also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can do it too.
Did you think that too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too portrays the idea of in excess or more than it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cat is too chubby.
The shoes were too expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To is used in expressions like to walk, to run, to paint, etc. (These are all verbs in their infinitive forms.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to run around the planet.
Did you tell her what to think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To is used in expressions like to the park, to the postman, agree to a proposal. (The word to in these examples is a preposition.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She handed the parcel to the stranger.
I am going to the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too much
Too many&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often use too before much and many. It means ‘more than necessary’. We can use too much before an uncountable noun and too many before a plural noun, or without a noun when the noun is obvious:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought too much food. We had to throw some of it away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a lot of work to do. Too much. (too much work)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are too many cars on the road. More people should use public transport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 35 children in each class. It’s too many. (too many children)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people drink coffee when they feel stressed. The warmth is soothing, and the caffeine in coffee might help you think more clearly. But if you drink too much, you may become even more anxious and irritable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a sentence or two using to, too and two.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Used to or use to.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/use-to-or-used-to/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/use-to-or-used-to/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;There is sometimes confusion over whether to use the form used to or use to, which has arisen largely because the pronunciation is the same in both cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except in negatives and questions, the correct form is used to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used to go to the movies all the time. (not we use to go to the movies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in negatives and questions using the auxiliary verb do, the correct form is use to, because the form of the verb required is the infinitive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t use to like mushrooms. (not I didn&amp;rsquo;t used to like mushrooms).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Using language metaphorically.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/using-language-metaphorically/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/using-language-metaphorically/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll have my fingers crossed for you when you sit your exam. I wish you luck and will be thinking about you when you take your exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have &amp;lsquo;green fingers&amp;rsquo;, it means you are very good at gardening and looking after flowers and plants (the metaphorical meaning) not that your fingers are the colour green (the literal meaning)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the money was stolen in the office, she pointed the finger at her colleague. She accused her colleague of stealing the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s really clever. He&amp;rsquo;s got every answer right at his fingertips. He knows the answers without having to think about them or research them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can count the friends she has on the fingers of one hand. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t have many friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;d better not lay a finger on him! Don&amp;rsquo;t hurt him!&lt;br&gt;
Note: This idiom is generally only used in the negative or question form; not in the positive form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s got her finger in every pie. I wish she would just concentrate on her own job instead. She&amp;rsquo;s over-involved in every project at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She works in advertising so she&amp;rsquo;s really got her finger on the pulse of today&amp;rsquo;s teenagers. She knows all about the current young people&amp;rsquo;s trends and fashions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Verb Tenses</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/verb-tenses/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/verb-tenses/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Verb tenses can be confusing, here is a brief summary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple present. She wants a drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present continuous. They are walking home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present perfect. I have lived here since 1987.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present perfect continuous. I have been living here for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfect continuous conditional. I would have been playing tennis if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t broken my arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple past. Peter lived in China in 1965.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past continuous. I was reading when she arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past perfect. We had been to see her several times before she visited us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past perfect continuous. He had been watching her for some time when she turned and smiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present continuous for future events. He isn&amp;rsquo;t working next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple present for future events. She&amp;rsquo;ll see you before she leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple future. They will go to Italy next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future with &amp;lsquo;Going to&amp;rsquo;. Is Freddy going to buy a new car soon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future continuous. I will be travelling by train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future perfect. We will have arrived in the Ukraine by the time you get this letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future perfect continuous. By the end of your course, you will have been studying for five years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Verb tenses - adding ed, ing.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/verb-tenses-adding-ed-ing/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/verb-tenses-adding-ed-ing/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The basic form of a verb is called the infinitive. It normally occurs with the word to as in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to ask you a question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbs may change their spelling according to which tense is being used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the past tense of regular verbs, the ending -ed is added to the infinitive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked her a question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the present participle, the ending -ing is added to the infinitive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am asking her a question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often there&amp;rsquo;s no need to make any other spelling changes when you add -ed and -ing to the infinitive but there are some cases when it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbs ending with a silent e&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the verb ends with an e that isn&amp;rsquo;t pronounced, as in bake or smile, then you need to drop this final -e before adding -ed and -ing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bake, baked, baking.&lt;br&gt;
smile , smiled, smiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbs ending in -ee, -ye, and -oe, such as free, dye, and tiptoe, do not drop the final -e when adding -ing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;free, freed, freeing.&lt;br&gt;
dye, dyed, dyeing.&lt;br&gt;
tiptoe, tiptoed, tiptoeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few verbs keep the final -e when adding -ing to distinguish them from similar words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;singe becomes singeing rather than singing (which is the present participle of sing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbs ending with a vowel plus -l&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the verb ends with a vowel plus -l, as in travel or equal, then you need to double the l before adding -ed and -ing in British English:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;travel, travelled, travelling.&lt;br&gt;
distil, distilled, distilling.&lt;br&gt;
equal, equalled, equalling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This rule doesn’t apply in American English&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbs ending with a single vowel plus a consonant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the verb ends with a single vowel plus a consonant, and the stress is at the end of the word, e.g. refer, then you need to double the final consonant before adding -ed and –ing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;admit , admitted, admitting.&lt;br&gt;
commit, committed, committing.&lt;br&gt;
refer, referred, referring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the verb ends with a vowel plus a consonant and the stress is not at the end of the word, you don’t need to double the final consonant when adding -ed and -ing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;inherit, inherited, inheriting.&lt;br&gt;
target, targeted, targeting.&lt;br&gt;
visit, visited, visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the verb has only one syllable and ends with a single vowel plus a consonant, e.g. stop, then you need to double the final consonant before adding -ed and -ing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;stop, stopped, stopping.&lt;br&gt;
tap, tapped, tapping.&lt;br&gt;
sob, sobbed, sobbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the verb ends with two vowels plus a consonant, you should generally not double the final consonant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;treat, treated, treating.&lt;br&gt;
wheel, wheeled, wheeling.&lt;br&gt;
pour, poured, pouring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbs ending in -c&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the verb ends in -c, e.g. panic, you need to add a -k before adding -ed and -ing, and also -er.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;picnic, picnicked, picnicking, picnicker.&lt;br&gt;
mimic, mimicked, mimicking, mimicker.&lt;br&gt;
traffic, trafficked, trafficking, trafficker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Verb Tenses, Past Perfect and Future Perfect.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/verb-tenses-past-perfect/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/verb-tenses-past-perfect/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The tense of a verb is determined by when the action took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple Present: They walk
Present Perfect: They have walked
Simple Past: They walked
Past Perfect: They had walked
Future: They will walk
Future Perfect: They will have walked&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three main tenses are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;past tense
present tense
future tense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past Perfect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past perfect tense designates action in the past just as simple past does, but the action of the past perfect is action completed in the past before another action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick raised vegetables and later sold them. (past)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick sold vegetables that he had raised. (past perfect)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vegetables were raised before they were sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yunni washed the car when Nick arrived (simple past)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yunni had washed the car when Nick arrived. (past perfect)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In (1), Yunni waited until Nick arrived and then washed the car. In (2), she had already finished washing the car by the time he arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sentences expressing condition and result, the past perfect tense is used in the part that states the condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I had done my exercises, I would have passed the test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Nick would have been elected if he hadn&amp;rsquo;t sounded so pompous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future Perfect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future perfect tense designates action that will have been completed at a specified time in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday I will finish my housework. (simple future)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By Sunday noon, I will have finished my housework. (future perfect)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yunni saved three hundred rupiah. (past)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yunni will save three hundred rupiah. (future)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yunni has saved three hundred rupiah. (present perfect)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yunni had saved three hundred rupiah by the end of last month. (past perfect)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yunni will have saved three hundred rupiah by the end of this month. (future perfect)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: There can be only one &amp;ldquo;would have&amp;rdquo; action group in a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>What is a paragraph?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/paragraphs/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/paragraphs/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A paragraph starts on a new line and is a distinct section of writing covering one topic, containing more than one sentence. A paragraph often starts with a topic sentence. It will have detail sentences in the middle and end with a concluding sentence. It will only cover one topic from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A paragraph is a collection of related sentences dealing with a single topic. Good paragraphing also greatly assists your readers in following a piece of writing. You can have fantastic ideas, but if those ideas aren&amp;rsquo;t presented in an organised fashion, you will lose your readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic rule with paragraphing is to keep one idea to one paragraph. If you begin to transition into a new idea, it belongs in a new paragraph. There are some simple ways to tell if you are on the same topic or a new one. You can have one idea and several bits of supporting evidence within a single paragraph. You can also have several points in a single paragraph as long as they relate to the overall topic of the paragraph. If the single points start to get long, then perhaps elaborating on each of them and placing them in their own paragraphs is the route to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elements of a paragraph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be as effective as possible, a paragraph should contain each of the following: Unity, coherence, a topic sentence, and adequate development. As you will see, all of these traits overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>What is an Adverb?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/what-is-an-adverb/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/what-is-an-adverb/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Improve your writing skills with adverbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My writing is so boring that even I don&amp;rsquo;t want to read it. How can I make my writing more interesting, appealing and attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;The man got in the car. He drove his car to the old house. He walked up to the door and knocked on it. The door opened.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is too little information here. Not only are these sentences unclear, they are also very boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do famous writers make their ideas and sentences so good that you are willing to spend 400,000 Rupiah just on one of their books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way good writers make their writing more interesting is to add adverbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An adverb is a word that describes how an action is done. The first sentence in the above example reads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;The man got in the car.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did the man get in the car?
Did he get in the car slowly, quickly, cowardly, ferociously, bravely, wildly, rowdily, quietly, loudly,brazenly, boldly, or shamelessly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By answering how the man got in the car, you describe the situation and readers can now visualise and understand the scene more clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;The man quickly got in the car. He peacefully drove his car to the old house. He happily walked up to the door and swiftly knocked on it. The door opened immediately.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was he a friend or foe (enemy)? A friend, of course. The words that tell us that he is probably a friend are quickly, peacefully, happily, swiftly, and immediately. It is the second and third adverbs that tell us this man is most likely a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s change the adverbs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;The man angrily got in the car. He frantically drove his car to the old house. He ferociously walked up to the door and loudly knocked on it. The door opened violently.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was he a friend or foe? He is most likely a foe. Again, it was the adverbs that told us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good writer is like an artist - he or she paints a picture in the reader&amp;rsquo;s mind using words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>What is Verb Conjugation?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/what-is-verb-conjugation/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/what-is-verb-conjugation/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most difficult aspects of learning English is the correct use of verbs. Few people understand this and those that do often go on to become professional writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conjugation is the changing of a verb&amp;rsquo;s form to show voice and mood, and to express a different person, number, tense, aspect, or gender. It is the form a verb takes to express action, and includes regular and irregular verbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to communicate in more than one tone, verbs must be conjugated. To conjugate something is to change a verb&amp;rsquo;s form to express a different meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, &amp;lsquo;am&amp;rsquo; is a present tense conjugation of the verb &amp;lsquo;be&amp;rsquo; and it is the form that goes with the subject &amp;lsquo;I.&amp;rsquo; Using &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo; (or &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo;) also indicates that the speaker is speaking in first person as opposed to second person (&amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo;) or third person (&amp;lsquo;he,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;she,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;it,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;they&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example using the verb to have:&lt;br&gt;
Let&amp;rsquo;s change the subject of this sentence:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;lsquo;We have a cat,&amp;rsquo; from &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;George&amp;rsquo;.&lt;br&gt;
We have a cat.&lt;br&gt;
George has a cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for the subject and verb to agree, we needed to change the verb &amp;lsquo;have&amp;rsquo; into &amp;lsquo;has&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In English, we have six different persons. We must conjugate a verb for each person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The verb to be is a particularly notable verb for conjugation because it’s irregular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbs are also conjugated according to their tenses. Verb tense indicates when the action in a sentence is happening (e.g., in the present, future, or past).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular verbs follow a standard pattern when conjugated according to tense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irregular verbs do not follow a standard pattern when conjugated according to verb tense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A conjugated verb expresses several different concepts. This is why it is important to use proper conjugation. Improper conjugation is very confusing to a reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In English, conjugation for &amp;lsquo;person&amp;rsquo; refers to the subject. Even though some languages do not require it, the English language requires that the subject be stated in every sentence (whether the subject is a noun or pronoun).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, conjugation changes depending on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conjugation for &amp;lsquo;number&amp;rsquo; refers to whether the verb is used with a singular or plural subject. The appropriate conjugation needs to be used depending on the number of the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aspect of a verb changes to express the degree to which an action is completed. In English, three aspects exist: simple, progressive, and perfect. Verbs are conjugated accordingly. Each aspect exists in the past, present, and future tenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English verbs and conjugation are unaffected by gender (male/female).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conjugation works differently for regular and irregular verbs. A regular verb is a verb that when conjugated follows a regular pattern. An irregular verb is a verb that when conjugated does not follow a regular pattern in the past tense or past participle conjugations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Which IELTS test is right for you?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/ielts-test/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/ielts-test/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two types of the IELTS test: IELTS Academic and IELTS General Training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IELTS Academic&lt;br&gt;
The IELTS Academic test is for people applying for higher education or professional registration in an English speaking environment. It reflects some of the features of academic language and assesses whether you are ready to begin studying or training. This approach is widely supported by the institutions that recognise IELTS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ELTS General Training&lt;br&gt;
The IELTS General Training test is for those who are going to English speaking countries for secondary education, work experience or training programs. It is also a requirement for migration to Australia, Canada, New Zealand and the UK. The test focuses on basic survival skills in broad social and workplace contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual organisations have different requirements. Make sure you check which IELTS test the organisation you are applying to recognises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IELTS test assesses your abilities in listening, reading, writing and speaking – in less than three hours. The Listening, Reading and Writing components of all IELTS tests are completed on the same day, with no breaks in between them. The Speaking component, however, can be completed up to a week before or after the other tests. Your test centre will advise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total test time is 2 hours and 45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening and Speaking are the same for both tests, but the subject matter of the Reading and Writing components differs depending on which test you take.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Which is correct, if I was or if I were?</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/were-or-was/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/were-or-was/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The question of whether to use if I was or if I were is a question of mood, which refers to the way in which a verb expresses an action or state of being. In the English language, sentences can take on three different moods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicative: This is the most common mood and the easiest to understand. The indicative mood makes statements or asks questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imperative: An imperative statement makes requests or gives commands. The subject of an imperative sentence is often an understood you that does not actually appear in the sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subjunctive: A verb in the subjunctive mood deals with hypothetical situations or with ideas that are contrary to fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present subjunctive, were is used for all people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subjunctive mood is the most common mood in the if I was/were dilemma, so if I were is more often (though not always) the best choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every if I statement should be in the subjunctive mood. Consider the following sentences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I was wrong, I apologise.&lt;br&gt;
If I were wrong, I would apologise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first sentence is in the indicative mood - it actually offers up the speaker&amp;rsquo;s apology. The second sentence, in the subjunctive mood, states either:&lt;br&gt;
a) that an apology would be forthcoming if the speaker&amp;rsquo;s error comes to light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or b) that the fact that the speaker hasn&amp;rsquo;t offered an apology indicates that he or she was not wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In either case, in this second sentence, the speaker&amp;rsquo;s error and apology are both hypothetical, and therefore the sentence is in the subjunctive mood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>While and The Subordinate Clause</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/while-and-the-subordinate-clause/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/while-and-the-subordinate-clause/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The subordinating conjunctions are: after, although, as, as if, because, before, even if, even though, if, if only, rather than, since, that, though, unless, until, when, where, whereas, wherever, whether, which, and while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;lsquo;while&amp;rsquo; creates a subordinating conjunction when it begins a sentence. The key is that it instantly makes the clause dependent whether it is independent or dependent, so you will have to follow it with an independent clause. When you attach a subordinate clause in front of a main clause, use a comma, like this:&lt;br&gt;
Subordinate Clause + , + Main Clause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;br&gt;
While Mary slept on the sofa in front of the television, Rover the family dog, gnawed on the leg of the coffee table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the snow just kept coming down, it was not accumulating as quickly as you would think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I did my homework, my father was washing the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While my parents drank coffee, my brother was watching TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;While&amp;rsquo; is the subordinate conjunction that introduces the subordinate clause, and because it appears at the beginning of the complete sentence, it is separated from the main clause with a comma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Who-whom-whose</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/who-whom-whose/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/who-whom-whose/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;To know whether to use &amp;lsquo;who&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;whom&amp;rsquo;, we need to understand the difference between subjects and objects because you use &amp;lsquo;who&amp;rsquo; when you are referring to the subject of a clause and &amp;lsquo;whom&amp;rsquo; when you are referring to the object of a clause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject of the sentence is the person doing something, and the object of the sentence is person having something done to them. If I kiss Mary, then I am the subject and Mary is the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;who = subject&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;whom = object&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;who = he/she&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;whom = him/her&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whose is a possessive pronoun. Use it when you&amp;rsquo;re asking (or telling) whom something belongs to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For whom are you making that cake?&lt;br&gt;
I am making this cake for him (or her).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George was the student whom the teacher liked best.&lt;br&gt;
The teacher liked him best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is going with you to the party?&lt;br&gt;
He (she) is going with me with to the party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know who is coming to see us?&lt;br&gt;
He is coming to see us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who wrote this article?&lt;br&gt;
Whom are you going to recommend?&lt;br&gt;
Whose book is on the table?&lt;br&gt;
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like this is the right address. Whom did you ask for directions?&lt;br&gt;
We have two extra tickets for the show. Who wants to go with us?&lt;br&gt;
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t me! I have no idea who left the stove on.&lt;br&gt;
Whose car is parked in the reserved parking space? If someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t move it, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be towed.&lt;br&gt;
The police have called in an expert to identify whose handwriting is actually on the ransom letter.&lt;br&gt;
Do you remember who received the award for best actor that year? Was it Tom Cruise?&lt;br&gt;
John couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember the name of the student whose history project received the first prize.&lt;br&gt;
I know exactly whom I&amp;rsquo;m going to support in the next election.&lt;br&gt;
That&amp;rsquo;s the doctor who spent 15 years living in the Amazon basin.&lt;br&gt;
He&amp;rsquo;s the actor whom she so vividly describes in her new book.&lt;br&gt;
Can you please tell me the names of the people who helped organise the picnic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The form &amp;lsquo;whom&amp;rsquo; is becoming less and less common in English. Many native English speakers think &amp;lsquo;whom&amp;rsquo; sounds outdated or strange. This trend is particularly common in the American English. Especially when combined with prepositions, most people prefer to use &amp;lsquo;who&amp;rsquo; as the object pronoun. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a valid word that we just need to learn how to use properly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Will or will be.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/will-will-be/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/will-will-be/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;We normally use WILL to speak about the future. It is always combined with another verb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WILL is classified as a modal verb like can, would, could, should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not change in the third person (i.e. he, she, it)
It is always combined with another verb in the base form (i.e. without &amp;lsquo;to&amp;rsquo;)
We don&amp;rsquo;t use it with &amp;lsquo;Do&amp;rsquo; in questions or negatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will go to the party tonight.
He will play soccer tomorrow.
She will be happy with her exam results.
They will take the bus to Jakarta next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use WILL in the following circumstances:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For things that we decide to do now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll call a taxi for you.
I think we&amp;rsquo;ll go right now. (I just decided this right now)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we think or believe something about the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President will not be re-elected at the next election.
I think it will rain later so take an umbrella with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To make an offer, a promise or a threat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You look tired. I&amp;rsquo;ll finish the housework for you.
If you say anything I will hit you!
I will have it ready by this evening.
I&amp;rsquo;ll drive you to work if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negative Sentences with WILL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the negative, we add NOT to the end of WILL and not to the main verb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not be in the office tomorrow. Correct
I will be not in the office tomorrow. Incorrect
They will not stay here. Correct
They will stay not here. Incorrect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WILL as a question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will they come?
Will they have arrived by now?
Will the work be finished soon?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Wish, would, wouldn&#39;t, will.</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/wish-would/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/wish-would/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I could see he was angry but he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t tell me what was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I invited him to the party but he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use wouldn&amp;rsquo;t in this way, it is softer in tone and sounds more natural than saying refused to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would = insisted on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The converse of wouldn&amp;rsquo;t is when, would indicates that someone insisted on doing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You WOULD go and tell her about the party, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you? You know I didn&amp;rsquo;t want her to know about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said you were unhelpful? Well, she WOULD say that, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t she?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can use would like this when we are being critical of someone&amp;rsquo;s past actions or behaviour. Note that it has to carry strong word stress when it is used in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;won&amp;rsquo;t / will&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar way, will can be used to talk about insistence when it relates to present situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you WILL eat so much, it&amp;rsquo;s not surprising that you&amp;rsquo;re fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you WILL decline the Invitation to Muriel&amp;rsquo;s wedding, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing I can do to stop you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this is one of the few occasions when will is used in the if-clause in conditional sentences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like wouldn&amp;rsquo;t for past situations, won&amp;rsquo;t can be used to talk about refusal when it relates to present situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t get these pictures to download. I keep clicking on this icon, but they won&amp;rsquo;t download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no good trying to persuade him. He won&amp;rsquo;t go and that&amp;rsquo;s that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that shan&amp;rsquo;t can be used in the first person as an alternative to won&amp;rsquo;t in this sense:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s invited me many times. But I shan&amp;rsquo;t go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s invited me many times, but I won&amp;rsquo;t go to her wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wish&amp;hellip; would&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also use wish with would and other modal verbs to express refusal combined with regret. Note that although we use past modal forms, the reference is to the present and future, here, not to the past:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish it would stop raining, but it just carries on. It&amp;rsquo;s been raining for days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t you wish this holiday might last forever? We&amp;rsquo;ve been having such a marvellous time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could give up smoking, but I can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish those two would shut up. They&amp;rsquo;ve been arguing like that for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody wishes he would stay away from June, but he won&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that to express regret about something which happened in the past, we can use wish with could have + past participle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish we could have seen the match live, but we just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get tickets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish my dad could have been here to see me play, but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t leave my mum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Writing an Email</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/writing-an-email/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/writing-an-email/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Email is the most common form of communication so it&amp;rsquo;s important to get it right. Although emails usually aren&amp;rsquo;t as formal as letters, they still need to be professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin with a greeting, thank the recipient, state your purpose, add your closing remarks and end with a closing statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin with a greeting, such as &amp;lsquo;Dear Mary&amp;rsquo;. If your relationship with the reader is formal, use their family name (eg. &amp;lsquo;Dear Mrs. Smith&amp;rsquo;). If the relationship is more casual, you can simply say, &amp;lsquo;Hi Mary&amp;rsquo;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name of the person you are writing to, use: &amp;lsquo;Dear Sir/Madam&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are starting the email communication, it may be difficult to include a line of thanks. Begin by stating your purpose, for example, &amp;lsquo;I am writing to enquire about&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;I am writing in reference to&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make your purpose clear early on, and then move into the main subject. Remember, people want to read emails quickly, so keep your sentences short and clear. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to pay careful attention to your grammar, spelling and punctuation so that you present a professional image of yourself and your company. Avoid using SMS texting abbreviations such as u, ur, lol, etc., and slang words such as wanna, gonna, shoulda, cos, bro, etc. Many people ignore or even delete email messages containing SMS and slang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you end your email, it&amp;rsquo;s polite to thank your reader one more time and add some polite closing remarks. You might start with &amp;lsquo;Thank you for your patience and cooperation&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Thank you for your consideration&amp;rsquo; and then follow up with, &amp;lsquo;If you have any questions or concerns, don’t hesitate to let me know&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;I look forward to hearing from you&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include an appropriate closing with your name. &amp;lsquo;Best regards&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Sincerely&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;Thank you&amp;rsquo; are all professional. Avoid closings such as &amp;lsquo;Best wishes&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Cheers&amp;rsquo; unless you are good friends with the reader. Finally, before you hit the send button, review and spell check your email one more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Mary,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your email this morning about learning English. I have recently started a website that may be of help to you, there are free English lessons, free corrections and many writing tips. Just click on this link &lt;a href=&#34;https://andrew9.com&#34;&gt;https://andrew9.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need further help please contact me, preferably by leaving a comment on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for interest, I look forward to hearing from you again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew McKean&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Writing Numbers</title>
       <link>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/quantities/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.zoom8888.com/lessons/quantities/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Except for a few basic rules, spelling out numbers is largely a matter of writers&amp;rsquo; preference, consistency is the key. The Associated Press Stylebook recommends spelling out the numbers zero through nine and using numerals thereafter. This is a complex topic, with many exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 1. Spell out all numbers beginning a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 2. Hyphenate all compound numbers from twenty-one through ninety-nine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 3. Hyphenate all written-out fractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 4. With figures of four or more digits, use commas. Count three spaces to the left to place the first comma. Continue placing commas after every three digits. Important: do not include decimal points when doing the counting. $1,345,234.45&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 5. It is not necessary to use a decimal point or a dollar sign when writing out sums of less than a dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 6. Do not add the word &amp;ldquo;dollars&amp;rdquo; to figures preceded by a dollar sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 7. For clarity, use noon and midnight rather than 12:00 PM and 12:00 AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 8. Using numerals for the time of day has become widely accepted.
The flight leaves at 6:22 a.m.
Please arrive by 12:30 sharp.
However, some writers prefer to spell out the time, particularly when using o&amp;rsquo;clock.
She takes the four thirty-five train.
The baby wakes up at five o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 9. Quantities less than 10 should be spelt out in full. She has one husband, three children, nine goats and 10 chickens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
 </channel>
</rss>
